这个男人值五百美金
This man is worth $500,
通缉  死活不拘
臭名昭著的罪犯
伯特·"小孩"·卡森
悬赏五百美金
而这个男人决心领赏
and this man's going to collect.
他就是杰克·卡希尔
He's Jake Cahill,
一个活在《赏金法》中的男人
and he lives by... Bounty Law.
你就是不能把他们活着带回来  是吧杰克
You don't ever bring them in alive, do you, Jake?
他们三打一  那可不行
Not when there's three of them and one of me.
你瞅啥  赏金杀手
What are you looking at, bounty killer?
一个下巴就要被我打碎的丑货
I'm looking at an ugly owl-hoot about to get his jaw busted.
业余的才抓活的
Amateurs try and take men in alive.
业余的一般成不了事
Amateurs usually don't make it.
不管你是死是活
Whether you're dead or alive,
你只是《赏金法》杰克·卡希尔眼中的赏金
you're just a dollar sign to Jake Cahill on Bounty Law.
《赏金法》
周四晚八点半
每周四八点半  精彩只在NBC电视台
Thursdays at 8:30, only on NBC.
大家好
Hello, everybody.
我是艾伦·金凯德
This is Allen Kincade
目前正在NBC和银幕珍宝旗下
on the set of the exciting hit NBC
大热电视剧集《赏金法》的片场
and Screen Gems television series Bounty Law.
如果你以为看到了重影
Now, if you think you're seeing double,
别着急调整你的电视机
don't adjust your television sets
其实你不算看走眼
because, well, in a way, you are.
我右手边的是《赏金法》主演
To my right is Bounty Law series lead
杰克·卡希尔的扮演者瑞克·道尔顿
and Jake Cahill himself, Rick Dalton.
而左手边是瑞克的替身  克利夫·布思
And to my left is Rick's stunt double, Cliff Booth.
欢迎二位  感谢抽时间
Welcome gentlemen and thanks for taking the time
-跟我们聊聊  -我们的荣幸  艾伦
- to visit with us. - It's our pleasure, Allen.
瑞克  能跟观众说说
So, Rick, explain to the audience
替身都具体做些什么吗
exactly what it is a stunt double does.
那个
Well...
演员需要做很多危险动作
actors are required to do a lot of dangerous stuff.
比如杰克·卡希尔中枪跌落马背
Say Jake Cahill gets shot off his horse.
我可以从马上摔下来吗
Now, can I fall off a horse?
当然可以  我也摔过
Yes, I can, and, yes, I have.
但如果我没摔对  扭了手腕
But say I fall off wrong and I sprain my wrist
或者脚踝
or I... or I twist my ankle.
就会对拍摄造成负担
Now, that can put an undue burden on production
因为我可能一周都没法工作
because now maybe I can't work for a week.
所以克利夫就是来帮我分担的
So Cliff here is meant to help carry the load.
克利夫  你也是这么认为的吗
Is that how you'd describe your job, Cliff?
帮他分担吗  没毛病
What, carrying his load? Yeah, that's about right.
下周我将去《迪克范戴克秀》的片场
Join me next week on the set of The Dick Van Dyke Show,
与莫雷·阿姆斯特丹和萝丝·玛丽
where I'll be talking to comical cutups,
两位活宝谈笑风生
Morey Amsterdam and Rose Marie.
艾伦·金凯德  好莱坞报道  再会
Till then, this is Allen Kincade signing off from Hollywood.
想死你了宝贝
I missed you.
黑色的  还有花的那个
The black one. And the flowers.
花  艾娃  花
Flowers, Ava, flowers.
还有小的那个
And there's the small one.
能看看你的票吗
Can I see your tickets?
好孩子
Oh, good boy.
1969年2月8日  星期六
吉娜  吉娜  吉娜
Gina, Gina, Gina.
朦胧之中动人的脸庞
The face in the misty light.
-你好  施瓦兹先生  -你好  吉娜
- Hello, Mr. Schwarz. - Hello, Gina.
我...来见一个牛仔小帅哥
I, uh... I have a meeting with a very handsome cowboy man.
他在吧台等您呢
He's waiting for you in the bar.
好啊
Well...
才看完瑞克·道尔顿的精彩电影
since I just finished watching a Rick Dalton fucking film festival,
我当然认得你  握个手吧
I think I know who you are. Put it there.
荣幸之至  施瓦茨先生
Well, it's my pleasure, Mr. Schwartz.
谢谢你赏脸
And thank you for taking an interest.
施瓦兹  不是施瓦茨
Schwarz, not Schwartz.
我的天啊  真不好意思
Ah. G-goddamn it to hell. I'm-I'm sorry about that.
-荣幸之至  施瓦兹先生  -叫我马文就行了
- It's my pleasure, Mr. Schwarz. - Call me Marvin.
马文  叫我瑞克就行了
Marvin, call me Rick.
-瑞克  -是的
- Rick? - Yeah.
-那是你儿子吗  -我儿子
- Oh, is that your son? - My son?
不  他是我替身  克利夫·布思
No, that's my stunt double, Cliff Booth. Yeah.
-幸会  -我们从《赏金法》的
- Good to meet you. - We've worked together
最后两季就一起共事
since the last two seasons of Bounty Law.
-是吗  -我车拿去修了
- Yeah? - My car's in the shop,
他载我过来的
so he gave me a ride.
胡扯
That's a big fucking lie.
瑞克因为酒驾次数太多被吊销了驾照
Rick got his driver's license taken away for too many drunk-driving tickets.
现在克利夫成了他司机
Cliff drives him everywhere now.
操
Oh, fuck.
真是个好朋友
Well, sounds like a good friend.
我尽量
I try.
我太太也问你好
I wanna send you greetings from my wife,
玛丽·爱丽丝·施瓦兹
Mary Alice Schwarz.
真好
Oh, well, that's nice.
十分感谢
Thanks a lot.
昨晚我俩在家里的放映厅
We had a Rick Dalton double feature
连看了两部瑞克·道尔顿电影
in our screening room last night.
承蒙厚爱  实在受之有愧
Oh, well, that's both flattering and-and embarrassing.
看了哪两部
What'd you see?
35毫米胶片的《坦纳》
Thirty-five mm prints of Tanner
和《麦克拉斯基的十四拳》
and The Fourteen Fists of McCluskey.
彩色电影
加州  好莱坞
《坦纳》
希望连看我这两部电影
I hope the, uh, Rick Dalton double feature
没让您太痛苦...还有您太太
wasn't too painful for you and the... and the missus.
"痛苦"  怎么会呢
Oh, no. "Painful." Stop. What are you saying?
玛丽·爱丽丝喜欢西部片
Mary Alice loves Westerns.
我俩约会那会儿看的全是西部片
Our whole courtship, we watched Westerns.
-给你  -谢谢
- Here you go. - Thanks.
我俩很喜欢《坦纳》
And we thoroughly enjoyed Tanner.
真好
Oh, that's nice.
非常棒  然后她睡觉去了
It's really good. And anyway, she goes to bed.
我开了一盒古巴雪茄
I open up a box of Havanas.
点上  到了杯干邑白兰地  然后看了
I light up, I pour myself a cognac and I watch...
《麦克拉斯基的十四拳》
The Fourteen Fists of McCluskey.
真好看
What a picture.
-棒极了  -是好电影
- What a picture. - Good picture, yeah.
太有意思了
That is so much fun.
激烈的枪战
All the shooting.
我喜欢杀戮
I love that stuff. You know, the killing.
的确有很多打打杀杀
A lot of killing. Lot of killing, yeah.
先生们  我们计划调转火力
Now, gentlemen, the plan is, we reverse our forces
把同盟国赶回海上去
und drive the Allies back into the sea!
天才
Genius.
装甲部队加入
Panzer divisions come in,
从这里把他们赶回海上
and we drive them here to the ocean.
他们被逼入绝路了
They'll be up against the wall.
-无路可退  -是的
- They will have nowhere to go. - Yes.
就是这里
This is the spot...
赫尔曼
Hermann!
帘子拉开
Open the curtains.
有人点了火烤德国泡菜吗
Anybody order fried sauerkraut?
烧成灰吧  纳粹杂种
Burn, you Nazi bastards!
用喷火器的人是你对吧
That's you operating the flamethrower, isn't it?
那还能是谁
Oh, you bet your sweet ass it was. Yeah.
-真的是你吗  -没错  我跟你说
- It was you? - Yeah. And let me tell you,
那武器真是屌爆了
that-that's one shit-fuck crazy weapon
碰到了就只有死翘翘
y-y-you do not wanna be on the wrong side of.
我的天
Boy, oh, boy.
我练习那武器
You know, I practiced with that dragon, uh,
整整两个星期  每天三小时
three hours a day for two weeks.
并不只是因为我想出镜时帅一些  更因为...
Not just because I wanted to look good in the picture, but because I was...
我其实怕的要死
I was shit-scared of the thing, to be honest.
我可是他妈的迈克·刘易斯
Mike fucking Lewis!
把这帮纳粹烧成灰
Crisping them Nazis to hell!
我操  太热了
Oh, shit, that's...
太热了
All right, that's too hot.
有没有什么办法降温
Anything we can do about that heat?
-瑞克  那可是喷火器  -好吧
- Rick, it's a flamethrower. - Yeah.
我今天很早就去了办公室
So I came to the office early today,
看了两集16毫米胶片的《赏金法》
and I watched two episodes of Bounty Law on 16 mm.
乔迪·贾尼斯
Jody Janice,
在怀俄明州因偷牛被通缉
wanted for cattle rustling in the state of Wyoming,
425美金  死活不拘
$425 dead or alive.
但你把他带来这里领赏
And you brought him here to collect.
我不知道这鬼地方是哪儿
I don't even know where here is.
随便找了个近的地儿
It was just the closest place.
我在五英里外的地方抓住了他
Caught up with him about five miles outside of town.
赏金杀手
So, bounty killer,
这小镇的名字叫贾尼斯镇
the name of this town is Janicetown.
你杀的那个男孩...
And that boy you killed...
就是乔迪·贾尼斯
was Jody Janice.
他是内森·麦斯威尔·贾尼斯少校的宝贝儿子
He was the baby boy of Major Nathin Maxwell Janice.
内森·麦斯威尔·贾尼斯少校什么来头
Who's Major Nathin Maxwell Janice?
他来了我一定好好介绍你
Well, I'll be sure and introduce you when he gets here.
《赏金法》
Bounty Law.
瑞克·道尔顿主演
Starring Rick Dalton.
然后档案室的蠢货送来了
Then a couple of the jokers over in archival sent over
你演的一个小节目的录像
a kinescope of a little treat featuring you.
*一架老钢琴*
*There's an old piano*
*他们在绿门之后弹奏*
*And they play it hot behind the green door*
*不知道他们在干嘛*
*Don't know what they're doing*
*但他们在绿门之后哈哈大笑*
But they laugh a lot behind the green door*
*希望他们能让我进去*
*Wish they'd let me in*
*让我看看绿门之后的奥秘*
*So I can find out what's behind the green door*
所以你过去几年都在电视剧里
So, uh, you've been doing guest shots
出演一些客串的角色吗
on episodic TV shows the last couple of years?
是的  我现在在为CBS台拍试播集
Yeah. Yeah. I'm doing a pilot f-for CBS right now.
剧名叫《兰瑟》  我演反派
It's called... It's called Lancer. I play the heavy.
演过罗恩·伊利的《泰山》
Did a, ahem, Ron Ely Tarzan.
《巨人大陆》  还有《青蜂侠》
I did a Land of the Giants. Green Hornet.
还有一部叫...
I did that show, uh...
斯科特·布朗演的《宾果·马丁》
Bingo Martin with that kid Scott Brown. Yeah.
还有一集《联邦调查局》这周日就播出
And I got a F.B.I. That-that airs this Sunday.
你在这些剧里都演反派吗
You, um... You always play the bad guy on these shows?
是的
Yeah.
片尾都有打斗戏吗
So, and they have a fight scene at the end of them?
不是...
Well, not... Not...
《巨人大陆》和《联邦调查局》没有
Not Land of the Giants or F.B.I.,
-其他有  没错  -你都打输了吗
- but the rest, yeah. Yeah. - And you lose in the fight?
那当然  我演的是反派
Yeah. Yeah, of course. I'm... I'm the heavy.
啊  电视台的老诡计了
Oh, that's an old trick pulled by the networks.
比如说《宾果·马丁》
Now, you take Bingo Martin, for example.
找了斯科特·布朗这个新人来演
So you got a new guy like Scott Brown.
想要打造他的知名度
You wanna build up his bona fides, right?
所以就从一个被砍的剧找个演员来演反派
So you hire a guy from a canceled show to play the heavy.
在片尾他们打架的时候
Then at the end of the show, when they fight,
让英雄战胜反派
it's hero besting heavy.
但观众看到的
But what the audience sees
是宾果·马丁把杰克·卡希尔打得落花流水
is Bingo Martin whipping Jake Cahill's ass.
明白了吗
You see?
下个星期是罗恩·伊利
Then next week, it's Ron Ely.
再下周是鲍勃·康拉德
And next week, it's Bob Conrad,
穿着紧身裤暴揍你
wearing his tight pants, kicking your ass.
是啊
Yeah.
你再给这些电视剧新星
Now, in another couple of years, playing punching bag
当两年沙包
to every swinging dick new to the network,
观众对你的印象
that's gonna have a psychological effect
就会受到影响  大打折扣
on how the audience perceives you.
没错
Right.
所以啊瑞克
So, Rick,
下周是谁把你胖揍一顿呢
who's gonna kick the shit out of you next week?
《万能神探》还是《秘密特工》
Mannix? The Man from U.N.C.L.E.?
还是《秘密女特工》
The Girl from U.N.C.L.E.?
《蝙蝠侠和罗宾》呢
How about Batman and Robin?
你被打趴下了
Down goes you.
你就别想当主演了
Down goes your career as a leading man.
还是去罗马  演演西部片
Or do you go to Rome and star in Westerns
好好赢几场
and win fucking fights?
小票  先生
Ticket, senor?
怎么了  伙伴
All right, what's the matter, partner?
穆索和弗兰克餐厅
好莱坞老字号
那个...
Well...
老兄  我终于明白了  我过气了
it's official, old buddy. I'm a has-been.
你说什么呢  那家伙跟你说啥了
What are you talking about? What did that guy tell you?
他给我讲了血淋淋的事实
He told me the goddamn truth, is what he told me.
-我的天  -该死
- Oh. Whoa. - Oh, shit.
对不起
I'm sorry about that.
Sorry about that.
来戴上
Here. Put these on.
别在墨西哥人面前哭
Don't cry in front of the Mexicans.
-他妈的  -你生什么气啊
- Son of a bitch. - What's got you so upset, man?
如果直面自己事业的失败时
Well, if coming face-to-face with the failure
都不能哭一场
that is your career ain't worth crying about,
那还有什么值得哭
then I don't know what the fuck is.
好吧  那家伙拒绝你了吗
Right. That guy in there turn you down?
没  他想帮我演意大利电影
No. He wants to help me get into Italian movies.
那不挺好吗
Then what's the problem?
我他妈居然去拍意大利电影
I gotta do Italian goddamn movies!
-好个屁  -得了吧
- That's the fucking problem! - Come on.
傻逼玩意  大庭广众哭怎么了
Fucking bullshit! It doesn't matter whether I cry in public.
好像还有人记得我似的
Nobody remembers who the fuck I am anyway, huh?
...在当地法院
...at the Hall of Justice here.
被告方试图证明肯尼迪被杀
The defense will try to prove the killing of Kennedy
-是精神失常的后果  -操
- was the product of a sick mind. - Fuck!
-谢谢  咱们走吧  -带我回家  克利夫
- Thank you. Hey, let's go. - Take me home, Cliff.
快带我回家
Come on, take me home.
越南南部爆发新的大规模战斗
More than 1000 Communists dead are reported
超过一千名越共死亡
in new, large-scale fighting in South Vietnam.
美军损失...
U.S. losses are said to be...
棒极了
That's swell, man.
去他妈的嬉皮士
Fucking hippie motherfuckers.
...及火箭和迫击炮基地
...and bases with rockets and mortar fire.
尼克森总统飞往欧洲时
As President Nixon was flying to Europe,
通过无线电收到了那场战斗的详情
he received details of that fighting by radio.
*永远即是永恒*
*Always is always forever*
*只要完全统一*
*As long as one is one*
*内心为了父亲*
*Inside yourself for your father*
*万物归一  万物归一  万物归一*
*All is one, all is one, All is one*
*我们该将爱抛诸脑后*
*It's time we put our love behind you*
*虚幻已经化作泡影*
*The illusion has been just a dream*
*死亡之谷  我将找到你*
*The Valley of Death and I'll find you*
*此刻阳光照耀*
*Now is when on a sunshine beam*
热狗面包
Hot dog buns!
*他们一定会看到*
*For sure they shall surely see*
*没有衣服  眼泪和饥荒*
*No clothing, no tears, no hunger*
*你们一定会看到  会看到  会看到*
*You shall see, you shall see, you shall see*
*永远即是永恒*
*Always is always forever*
*只要完全统一*
*As long as one is one*
*内心为了父亲*
*Inside yourself for your father*
*万物归一  万物归一  万物归一*
*All is one, all is one, All is one*
走了五年上坡路
Five years of ascent.
摸爬滚打十年
Ten years of-of-of treading water.
现在跌入谷底
And now a race to the bottom. Heh.
我没什么可说的职业经历
Look, I never had much of a career to speak of,
我没法说我懂你的感受
so I can't say I really know how you feel.
你说什么  你可是我的替身
What are you talking about? You're my stunt double.
-得了吧  -靠
- Come on, now. - Shit.
瑞克  我是你的司机  帮你跑腿
Rick, I'm your driver, man. I'm-I'm your gofer.
我不是在抱怨  我喜欢载你到处跑
I'm not complaining, man. I like driving you around.
我喜欢在你不在的时候
I like doing shit around the house
帮你看着好莱坞山的房子
and house-sitting in the Hollywood Hills when you're gone.
但我已经好久不做全职替身了
But I haven't been a full-time stuntman for a while now,
就我目前的状况来说
and from where I'm standing,
去罗马演电影
going to Rome to star in movies does not sound
没有你想的那么严重
like the fate worse than death that you seem to think it is.
拜托  你看过意式西部片吗
Come on, now. You ever seen an-an Italian Western, huh?
很差劲  就是胡闹
They're awful. It's a fucking farce.
你看过几部  一部  两部
Yeah, how many you seen? One? Two?
我看得够多了好吧  没人喜欢意式西部片
I've seen enough, all right? Nobody likes Spaghetti Westerns.
天堂道
留在洛杉矶吧
Oh, hell, man, stay in L.A.
等到下个试播季
Give it what fer next pilot season.
不了  我
Nah, nah. I'm... I'm...
我很怕下个试播季还是没人要
I'm too insecure now to score come pilot season.
银幕珍宝公司对我不会嘴下留情
Screen Gems ain't gonna have nothing good to say about me.
-你清楚的  -靠  你拍了《赏金法》
- You know that. - Shit. You made Bounty Law.
没人会原谅我在最后一季做的事
Nobody's gonna forgive me for that last season.
无论我怎么做
No matter what I do...
都摆脱不了这个骂名
...I'm always gonna be the horse's ass
我害《赏金法》被砍了
that got Bounty Law canceled
因为我他妈的想进军大银幕
because I wanted some fucking rinky-dink movie career.
-汤姆  我的朋友  -我认识他吗
- Tom. My friend. - I met him?
你不认识
No, you haven't met him.
你不会见他的  因为我觉得
You won't meet him because I don't think
-你不会喜欢他  -为什么
- you'd like him. - Why?
好吧
Well...
天啊
Holy shit.
那是波兰斯基
That was Polanski.
那是罗曼·波兰斯基[著名导演]
That was Roman Polanski.
他在那里住了一个月了
He's lived there for a month now.
这是我第一次见到他
First time I seen him.
天啊  靠
Holy shit. Goddamn it.
我常说什么来着
What do I always say?
在这座城市最重要的事
Most important thing in this town is,
就是赚了钱就买栋房子
when you're making money, you buy a house in town.
别租房  艾迪·奥布莱恩教我的
You don't rent. Eddie O'Brien taught me that.
有好莱坞的房产意味着你落脚了
Hollywood real estate means you live here.
你不只是游客  不只是过客
You're not just visiting, not just passing through.
你他妈落脚了
You fucking live here.
看我累死累活的
Here I am flat on my ass,
我旁边又住着谁呢
and who I got living next door to me?
正是他妈的《罗丝玛丽的婴儿》的导演
The director of Rosemary's fucking Baby, that's who.
波兰斯基  这里目前最热门的导演
Polanski, the hottest director in town right now,
或许是全世界最热门的
probably the world.
居然是我的邻居
He's my next-door neighbor.
靠  谁知道以后会怎样
I mean, shit. I mean, who knows what could happen?
我可能离出演波兰斯基的新电影
I could... I could be one pool party away
只差一场泳池派对了
f-from starring in a new Polanski movie.
你现在好些了吗
So you're feeling better now?
是  刚刚很抱歉
Aw, yeah, yeah. Sorry about all that.
还我眼镜
Give me my glasses back.
过来拿啊  傻逼
Oh, come get them, fucker. Come...
好了  奥迪·墨菲[二战英雄]  别激动
All right, all right, Audie Murphy, relax.
-给你  -你还需要我干嘛吗
- There you go. - You need me for anything else?
不用了  我得为明天熟悉台词
Nah, nah, nah. I got a lot of lines to learn for tomorrow.
-靠  -行吧
- Shit. - All right.
我累死了  回家了
I'm gonna get my carcass on home.
-行  -行  明早七点十五
- All right. - All right, 7:15 A.M.
-七点十五  -门外见
- Seven-fifteen. - Out the door.
-门外见  -车里
- Out the door. - In the car.
行  再见
All right, see you then.
巴诺拉马城
范奈斯露天影院
《水泥中的女士》
你好  请进
Hello, coming in. Hello.
你好啊  亲爱的
Hello, darling. Hello.
过来
Come here.
你好  大宝贝
Hello, sweetheart.
你今天过得怎么样
How was your day?
等等  看我给你带了什么
Wait till you see what I got for you.
看我给你带了什么好东西
Wait until you see what I got for you.
看看这个
Look what I got for you.
会吓你一跳
Gonna blow your mind, man.
过来  过来
Come here. Come here.
狼牙牌狗粮
《三女争一夫》
那是发牢骚吗
Was that a whine?
我说了发牢骚会怎样
What did I tell you about whining?
发牢骚就饿肚子
You whine, you don't eat.
我就把这东西扔进垃圾桶
I will throw this shit in the trash.
我也不想  但我会这么做
I don't wanna, but I will.
明白吗
You understand?
行
All right.
《电视指南》
混乱的电视圈
我在酒吧等到打烊
I waited at the bar till closing time,
他还是没回来
but he never came back.
佩吉  怎么了
Okay, Peggy, what happened?
不知道  没什么问题
I don't know. Everything was fine.
我们在我家吃了饭
We had dinner at my house.
之后就
And afterwards, you know,
我洗碗的时候
while I was doing the dishes,
他和托比在玩
he and Tobey played.
然后在俱乐部  盖布表现不错
And then, at the club, Gabe was doing great.
再就画风突变
Then, wham, a sudden change.
音乐家就这样  性情捉摸不定
You know how musicians are. They're temperamental cats.
-谁知道他受什么气了  -是啊
- Who knows what got into him? - Yeah.
瑞克·道尔顿彩排带  五  四
Rick Dalton rehearsal tape starting in five, four,
三  二  一
three, two, one.
佩佩  到吧台来  我有客人
Pepe, get your behind behind that bar! I got a guest.
约翰尼说...
Johnny says...
[西语  西语  西语]
Spanish, Spanish, Spanish.
豆子怎么样
How's the beans?
还凑合
I've had worse.
约翰尼说...[西语]
Johnny says... Spanish.
敬酒
A toast.
敬我的妻子  和我所有的宝贝
To my wife and all my sweethearts.
愿她们永不相见
May they never meet.
马德里先生  来我这桌吧
Senor Madrid, care to join me at my table
这是我招待客人的地方
where I entertain my guests?
我很乐意  达科塔先生
I would be delighted, Monsieur Dakota.
带上酒瓶一起
Take the bottle with you.
佩佩走过来
And Pepe comes over.
你那个惹火的女儿呢
Hey, where's that chili pepper daughter of yours
会拉小提琴那个
with the fiddle?
睡着了
She's asleep.
叫醒她  让她下来
Well, wake her the heck up, get her down here
带上小提琴和琴弓  给客人露一手
with her fiddle and her bow, and entertain my guests.
好的  先生  但拜托这次别伤害她
Si, senor, but please don't hurt her this time,
我求你
I beg you.
我不会伤害她
I ain't gonna hurt her.
只想让她拉提琴
Just want her to play the fiddle.
叫她来  告诉她我会给她
Fetch her and tell her I'll give her
整整五美金
a fat $5 gold piece,
让她带着火辣的感情拉提琴
she play her little chili pepper heart out.
约翰尼  你还听说了些什么
So, Johnny, what else you heard about me?
我听说你把兰瑟逼得很紧
I heard you're pushing Lancer pretty hard,
但兰瑟很有钱
but Lancer has money.
他总有一天会雇人报仇的
At some point, he's gonna hire some guns and push back.
-不好意思  -没事
- Oops, sorry. - It's okay.
我给你开门
I'll open the door for you.
你气色不错
You look good.
我觉得史蒂夫也会过去
I think Steve's gonna be there too.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
看  他们来了
Oh, look. They're here.
花花公子宅邸
史蒂夫·麦奎因[演员]
米歇尔·菲利普斯[演员/歌手]
杰·赛百灵[发型师]
欢迎来到花花公子宅邸  波兰斯基先生
Welcome to the Playboy Mansion, Mr. Polanski.
你好啊  宝贝
Hey, how are you doing, baby?
你好呀
How are you?
卡斯
Cass!
好耶
Yeah!
好耶  宝贝
Yeah, baby!
我给你讲个故事
I'm gonna tell you a story.
她本来跟他订婚了
She was engaged to him.
然后她飞去了英国
Then she flew to the UK...
跟他一起拍电影
to make a film with him,
然后就跟他取消了婚约  嫁给了他
and broke off her engagement with him and married him.
然后他们搬来了洛杉矶
Then they moved to Los Angeles,
他们三人
and the three of them
从未分开
have been inseparable.
真的吗
Really?
怎么回事
What's up?
杰爱莎伦  就是这么回事
Jay loves Sharon, that's what's up.
他很肯定
And he knows...
像上帝创造了小青苹果那样肯定
as sure as God made little green apples...
总有一天  那个波兰佬
that one of these days, that Polish prick's
会搞砸事情
gonna fuck things up,
等他搞砸  杰就上场
and when he does, Jay's gonna be there.
有一件事是肯定的
Well, one thing's for sure.
是吗
Yeah?
怎么了
What's that?
莎伦绝对喜欢一种类型
Sharon absolutely has a type.
就是帅气有才的矮个
Cute, short, talented guys
像十二岁小男孩那种
who look like 12-year-old boys.
没错
Yeah.
所以我没机会
I never stood a chance.
1969年2月9日  星期日
去你的  萨皮斯坦博士
Fuck you, Dr. Sapirstein.
我们到了
Here we are.
告诉运输工  得全部搬出去
Tell transpo! Gonna need to move all that out!
等会儿  等等  各位
Just a sec. Hold on, guys.
去吧
Go ahead.
你可以跟他谈谈  就跟他谈
You can talk to him. Just talk to him.
准备好布景
Get that set in place.
昨晚风把电视天线吹倒了
I think the wind blew down my TV antenna last night,
我去试妆的时候
so while I piss-fart around with wardrobe,
你介意回家修理吗
you mind going home and fixing it?
行  你今天问问替身领班行吗
I can. You talk to the stunt gaffer about me today?
我才知道这周有没有工作
That way I'll know if I'm working this week or not.
是  我一直想告诉你
Yeah. Ahem. I've been meaning to tell you.
管这事的人  他是兰迪的哥们
The guy who gaffs this, he's best friends with Randy,
《青蜂侠》的领班
the gaffer from The Green Hornet...
所以...没什么意义
...so there ain't no point.
如果没我其他啥事  那我等收工来接你
If you don't need me for anything else, I'll pick you up at wrap.
今天没啥事
I don't need you. Not today.
去我家修天线吧  随你  收工见
Go home, fix my antenna, do whatever. See you at wrap.
你他妈是瑞克·道尔顿  可别忘了
You're Rick fucking Dalton. Don't you forget it.
兄弟  我是瑞克·道尔顿
Hey, buddy, I'm Rick Dalton.
你知道我该去哪儿吗
You know where I'm supposed to go?
他们在化妆车里等着你
They're waiting for you in the makeup trailer.
化妆车在哪里
Where's the makeup trailer?
你过来的那条路往回走  右拐
Straight back the way you came, hard right.
天啊
Oh, my God.
瑞克·道尔顿
Rick Dalton.
山姆·沃纳梅克
Sam Wanamaker.
山姆
Hey, Sam.
抱歉  我手湿了
Sorry about the wet hand.
没事  我都习惯尤尔这样了
Oh, don't worry. I'm used to it with Yul.
我希望你知道  是我挑了你
I want you to know, I'm the one who cast you.
我非常高兴你能来演
And I couldn't be more delighted you're doing this.
谢谢你  山姆
Oh, well, thank you, Sam.
我很感激  这角色很不错
I... I appreciate it. It's a good part.
没错  见过吉姆·斯泰西吗  主演
Yeah, it is. Have you met Jim Stacy, the series lead?
还没有  没
Uh, not yet, no. No.
你们一起会打个热火朝天的
Well, you guys are going to be dynamite together.
听起来很火爆
Well, it sounds exciting.
没错  激烈的碰撞
Yeah, lightning in a bottle.
这是索尼娅  化妆发型师
Now, you met Sonya, makeup and hair?
你好
Hi.
-这是瑞贝卡  服装师  -你好
- And this is Rebekka, who does costumes. - Hello.
-你好  -好啊
- Hi. - Howdy.
我希望给卡勒布做全新造型
I want a whole new look for Caleb.
我不希望这部西部片的造型
I don't want this Western costumed
撞了《大峡谷》和《伯南扎的牛仔》
the way they costumed The Big Valley
过去十多年的造型
and Bonanza for the last decade.
我希望赋予造型时代精神
I want a zeitgeist flair to the costumes.
不会与当时不符
I mean, nothing anachronistic,
1869年和1969年的共同点是什么
but where does 1869 and 1969 meet?
特别是涉及到你时  卡勒布
Especially when it comes to you, Caleb.
首先  我要他留小胡子
First off, I want to give him a mustache.
浓密  下垂  墨西哥革命领袖萨帕塔那样的
A big, droopy, Zapata-like mustache.
然后是他的外套
Now, about his jacket.
我想让他穿嬉皮士外套
I want to give him a hippie jacket.
他若是今晚穿着走进伦敦雾夜总会
Something he could wear into the London Fog tonight
就会是全场最嬉皮的人
and look like the hippest guy in the room.
南北战争的传奇人物
好  我们有件卡斯特将军的外套
Far out. We got a Custer jacket.
袖子坠满流苏
Fringes all down the arm.
现在变成棕黄色了  但只要我染成深棕色
It's tan now, but I dye it dark brown,
他今晚就能穿着去拉斯维加斯
he could hit the Strip in it tonight.
好姑娘
That's my girl.
-瑞克  还有你的头发  -我的头发怎么了
- Now, Rick, about your hair. - What about my hair?
我想给你换个发型
I want to go with a different hairstyle.
什么
What?
换个更嬉皮的
Something more hippie-ish.
你想把我打扮成嬉皮士吗
You want me to look like a hippie?
别想成嬉皮士  而是...
Well, think less hippie, more...
地狱天使机车帮
Hells Angel!
-好吧  山姆  如果...  -给我...
- Right. Say, Sam... - Get me the...
山姆  山姆
Sam. Sam, uh...
如果你让我从头到脚换上这些...
if you got me covered up in all this...
垃圾
this junk, uh,
观众到时怎么知道是我呢
how's the audience gonna know it's me?
我就希望他们不知道
I hope they don't.
我不要他们看见杰克·卡希尔
I don't want them to see Jake Cahill.
我要他们看见卡勒布
I want them to see Caleb.
我是请你来当演员的  瑞克
I hired you to be an actor, Rick.
不是三流电视牛仔  你比那优秀多了
Not a TV cowboy. You're better than that.
《战斗》
每周日1:00-2:00播出
我一直想告诉你  管这事的人
I've been meaning to tell you, the guy who gaffs this,
他是兰迪的哥们
he's best friends with Randy,
《青蜂侠》的领班
the gaffer from The Green Hornet,
所以...没什么意义
so there really ain't no point.
兰迪
Hey, Randy.
克利夫
Cliff.
看来你还在跟着瑞克混啊
So you're still with Rick, huh?
还在这呢
Still here.
他在里面吗
He in there?
在  敲门就行
Yeah. Just knock.
听我说  就安排他去服装部  好吗
Look, just put him in the wardrobe, all right?
能有什么坏处呢
What's it gonna hurt?
之后如果你有需要  他就派上用场了
Then if you need him, you got him, all right?
但这样我就得跟
But then I gotta have a conversation
服装部助理沟通
with that wardrobe assistant,
要知道  那个婆娘可贱了
and, man, she's a fucking bitch.
我不想...  拜托了
I just don't... Please, I...
听着  兰迪  我在求你帮忙
Look, Randy, I'm asking you to help me out, man.
如果你要拒绝  就直接拒绝
If the answer's no, the answer's no,
别找借口
not no with excuses.
哥们
Hey, man.
这可不是名导安德鲁·麦克拉格伦的电影
This ain't a fucking Andy McLaglen picture, you know?
我请不起一群一天到晚只在片场
I can't afford to hire a bunch of guys to smoke cigarettes
坐着抽烟聊天的闲人
and sit around talking to each other all day
只因为他们也许派得上用场
on the chance that I might use them.
我的团队已经有四个人  瑞克
I got a four-man team here, Rick.
如果我需要更多人手  就得去申请
If I need more than that, I gotta get it approved.
你也知道  我得罩着我的兄弟们
And, you know, I gotta look after my dudes.
如果你那些兄弟更适合当我的替身
Hey, and if your dudes were a better match for me,
我会欣然接受
I'd say, "Okay, you got me,"
但情况不是这样  你也心知肚明
but-but that's not the case, and you know it.
-他是最适合的人选  -可是...
- He's a great match for me. - Yeah, no...
你想叫他做什么都行
Hey, you could do anything you want to him.
从高楼跳下去  在身上点火
Throw him off a building, right? Light him on fire.
哪怕开车撞他也没问题
Hit him with a fucking Lincoln, right?
发挥创意  你想怎么样都可以
Get creative. Do whatever you want.
他能得到这个机会就很开心了
He's just happy for the opportunity.
-瑞克  -什么
- Rick. - Yeah?
我不喜欢他
I don't dig him.
也不喜欢他带到片场的气氛
And I don't dig the vibe he brings on a set.
怎么  你们以前有过节吗
What, is there some old beef between the two of you?
-得了吧  兄弟  -怎么了
- Oh, come on, man. - What? What?
那家伙杀了自己的老婆
The dude killed his fucking wife.
老传闻你也信
Come on, man. You don't believe that old shit, do you?
我真信  瑞克
Yes, Rick, I do.
我和我老婆共事  她也相信
And I work with my wife, and she believes it.
她不希望那个小人来
She doesn't want his creepy ass around.
这估计是史上最糟糕的天气了
You know, this is probably the shittiest weather ever.
在最糟糕的天气里  和一个人品最恶劣的人
The shittiest weather on the shittiest boat
一起待在一艘最破烂的船上
with the shittiest person.
我姐妹娜塔莉说  "他就是个废物"
Natalie, my sister, said, "He's a loser. He's a loser."
他们都这么说  "他丫就是个废物"
They all said it, "He's a fucking loser,"
我之前还不相信他们
and I didn't believe them.
所以愚蠢的人是我
So I guess I'm the fucking idiot.
现在你还不理我了
And now you're not gonna talk to me?
怎么  你不想吵架吗
What, you don't feel like fighting?
但我他妈想吵架
Well, I feel like fucking fighting
因为我已经独自一人
because I've been up here by myself
在这艘破船上待了整整四小时了
for four hours on this fucking shithole of a boat.
好吧
Yeah.
他可是战争英雄啊  操
H-he's a goddamn war hero. Fuck.
非常感谢
Yeah, appreciate it.
你这个脓包  我带你去服装部吧
Okay, you fucking horse's ass. Let's get you over to wardrobe.
你先待在服装部
Now, I'll put you in wardrobe,
但你没做替身  我就不付你薪水
but you don't stunt, I don't pay you.
谢谢你给我机会  兰迪  我不会让你失望的
Appreciate the opportunity, Randy. I won't let you down.
你认识我老婆珍妮特  对吧
You know my wife Janet, don't you?
是的
Yeah.
别让她看见你
Steer clear of her.
拳王阿里本名
我很欣赏卡修斯·克莱  真的
Now, I admire Cassius Clay, I do.
我欣赏的是  在他的运动里
What I admire is, in his sport,
有真实的格斗成分
there's an element of true combat.
卡修斯·克莱和索尼·利斯顿在擂台上相遇时
When Cassius Clay meets Sonny Liston in the ring,
不是两名运动员在装模作样
that's not two athletes posturing.
而是格斗
That's combat.
那是两个男人在互相厮杀
Two men trying to kill each other right now.
如果你不打败他
If you don't beat him...
他就会杀了你
he kills you.
那远超过竞技范畴
That's beyond athletics.
那远超过体育节目
That's beyond Wide World of Sports, you know?
那是两名战士展开致命搏斗
That's two warriors engaged in combat.
我欣赏的就是这一点
That's what I admire.
在武术比赛里
In martial arts tournaments,
是不允许这样搏斗的
they won't let you fight like that.
非常令人沮丧
It's very frustrating.
你站在对手面前
You stand in front of a guy,
你很想让他尝尝你的厉害
and you just wanna let him have it. Ha!
但你不能
But you can't.
你只能展示些花拳绣腿
So you gotta do this playacting, patty-cake version.
卡修斯·克莱  索尼·利斯顿  乔·路易斯
Cassius Clay. Sonny Liston. Joe Louis.
我是指那个黑人拳手
The colored boxer,
不是玩跆拳道那个混蛋白人
not that white kickboxing asshole.
他们为了赢  不择手段
They do what they need to do to win.
为击败对手
They unleash as much punishment
他们拼尽全力  毫不留情
as they have to to defeat the other guy.
但在武术比赛中
But in martial arts tournaments,
我也跟他们一样拼全力去赢
I do to win what they do to win.
我会释放出全部实力
I unleash all my power.
我会夺人性命
I kill people.
如果你和卡修斯·克莱对战  谁会赢
If you fought Cassius Clay, who would win?
那绝不会发生
Well, that would never happen.
但如果真交手  你觉得会有什么结果
But if you did, what do you think would happen?
我会把他打成瘸子
I'd make him a cripple.
你  你叫什么
Hey, you. What's your name?
-我吗  -对  你
- Me? - Yeah, you.
我叫克利夫
My name's Cliff.
我是瑞克·道尔顿的特技替身
I'm Rick Dalton's stunt double.
-特技人  -没错
- Stuntman? - Yeah.
你这个特技替身未免太过帅气了
You know, you're kind of pretty for a stuntman.
他们也是这么说的
That's what they tell me.
我说了什么可笑的话吗  特技人
So did I say something funny, stuntman?
-算是吧  -什么事这么好笑
- Yeah, you kind of did. - What's so funny?
我不想惹麻烦
Look, man, I don't want any trouble.
我只是来干活的
I'm just here to do a job.
但你在嘲笑我说的话
But you're laughing at what I'm saying.
可我并没说什么可笑的话
But I'm not saying anything funny.
你到底觉得有什么好笑的
So, what do you think is so funny?
我觉得...
What I think is...
你这人个子虽小  口气倒不小
you're a little man with a big mouth and a big chip,
而且你该感到羞愧
and I think you should be embarrassed
你只配当卡修斯·克莱
to suggest you'd be anything more than a stain
拳击短裤上的污渍
on the seat of Cassius Clay's trunks.
兄弟  你的口气才狂妄
Brother, you're the one with the big mouth.
我很愿意让你闭嘴
And I would really enjoy closing it,
特别是当着我所有朋友的面
especially in front of all my friends.
但我这双手被视为致命武器
But my hands are registered as lethal weapons.
那意味着  如果我们交手
That means, we get into a fight,
我不小心杀了你  我就得坐牢
I accidentally kill you, I go to jail.
任何人在交手过程中
Anybody accidentally kills anybody
不小心杀了人  都得坐牢
in a fight, they go to jail.
这叫过失杀人
It's called manslaughter.
而且我认为"致命武器"只是借口
And I think all that "Lethal weapon" horseshit is just an excuse
让你们这些没真本事的不用来真的
so you dancers never have to get in a real fight.
好吧
Okay.
那来一场友好较量如何
How about a friendly contest?
不打脸
No punching in the face.
三局两胜
Two out of three.
看谁先将对方打趴下
Who puts who on the ground first?
不故意伤害对方  只是看谁先倒地
Nobody tries to hurt nobody, just who ends up on their butt?
李小龙在《青蜂侠》中饰演的角色
这主意真棒  加藤
That's a great idea, Kato.
布鲁斯  那家伙挺有名的
You know, Bruce, that guy's kind of famous.
那家伙
That guy?
为什么
For what?
杀了他妻子后逍遥法外
Killed his wife and got away with it.
那家伙吗
That guy?
对
That guy.
不错嘛  加藤
Not bad, Kato.
再试一次
Try that again.
等一下  等一下
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
这他妈是什么情况
What the fuck is going on here?
混球  这是我们的主演
Hey, jackass, this is our series lead.
你他妈在想什么呢
What the fuck are you thinking?
你说得对  珍妮特  我很抱歉
You're right, Janet. I'm sorry about that.
别他妈叫我珍妮特  混蛋
Don't fucking "Janet" me, you prick.
怎么了  宝贝
Hey. What's up, babe?
兰迪  你的废物杀妻好友
What's up, Randy, is that your loser asshole,
刚才痛揍了布鲁斯
wife-killing buddy boy here was beating the shit out of Bruce.
什么
What?
-兰迪  -克利夫
- Hey, Randy. - Cliff.
搞什么鬼
What the fuck, man?
我要说一下  没人能痛揍布鲁斯
Let me just say, nobody beat the shit out of Bruce.
刚才只是场友好较量  他几乎都没碰到我
It was a friendly contest. He barely touched me.
车上那凹痕可不是这么说的
I think that dent in the car says something different.
我的老天啊
Oh, my God!
你他妈对我的车做了什么
What the fuck did you do to my car?!
你他妈对她的车做了什么
What the fuck did you do to her car?
我把这个小混球砸到车上了
I threw this little prick into it,
但我不知道那是她的车
but I did not know it was her car.
把服装脱了  拿上你的东西  去死吧
Get the wardrobe off, get your shit, and get fucked!
-珍妮特  -干什么
- Janet! - What?
我来处理
I will handle this.
那你他妈赶紧处理  兰迪
Then fucking handle it, Randy.
克利夫
Cliff...
把服装脱了  拿上你的东西
get the wardrobe off, get your shit,
滚出片场
and get off the lot.
好吧
Fair enough.
怎么了
Aw. What's the matter?
"大门"乐队主唱
你担心我会告诉吉姆·莫里森
Are you afraid I'll tell Jim Morrison you were dancing
你听着保罗·瑞佛和奇袭者乐队的歌跳舞吗
to Paul Revere and the Raiders?
他们对你来说不够酷吗
Are they not cool enough for you?
这个头发蓬乱的混蛋是谁
Who's this shaggy asshole?
你好  有什么事吗
Hello? Can I help you?
对  我想找泰瑞
Oh, yeah. Hey, man. I'm looking for Terry.
海滩男孩乐队的鼓手
我是泰瑞和丹尼斯·威尔逊的朋友
I'm a friend of Terry's and Dennis Wilson's.
泰瑞和坎蒂已经搬走了
Well, Terry and Candy don't live here anymore.
现在这里是波兰斯基的家
This is the Polanski residence now.
真的吗  他搬走了
Really? He moved?
该死
Dang.
你知道他搬去哪了吗
Uh, you know...? You know where?
我不确定  但这里的业主保罗可能知道
I'm not sure, but the owner of the property, Paul, might.
他在客房
He's in the guest house.
是谁啊  杰
Who is it, Jay?
没事  亲爱的  是泰瑞的朋友
It's okay, honey. It's a friend of Terry's.
对  走后面的小路
Yeah, just take the back path.
非常感谢
Thank you kindly.
女士再见
Ma'am.
-休息一小时  -瑞克
- All right, that's an hour! - Hey, Rick.
我知道现在是午餐时间
I know they just broke for lunch,
但你得等至少一小时才能吃
but you need to wait at least an hour before you can eat.
-先让胶水晾干  -别担心  亲爱的
- Give that glue a chance to dry. - Oh, no worries, honey.
我带着书呢  对了  坏人酒吧在哪
I got my book. Say, say, where's the bad-guy saloon?
直走穿过西部小镇
You just go straight through the Western town,
右转再左转  就能看到了
take a right and a left, and you see it right there.
谢了  宝贝
Thanks, honey.
他弹跳怎么样
How is his bounce?
能在那里装个弹跳装置吗
Can I get a bounce there?
我去拿个可调扳手  马上回来
Just grab the crescent wrench, come right back.
尽快
Just make it a quick one.
-蒂姆  -看着不错  就是那里
- Tim! - Looks great. Right there.
特鲁迪·弗雷泽
你好
Hello.
如果...
Would...
我坐在你旁边看书会打扰到你吗
Would it bother you if I sat next to you and read my book too?
我不知道
I don't know.
你会打扰我吗
Would you bother me?
我尽量不打扰你
I'll try not to.
坐吧
Sit.
对不起  不好意思
Sorry. Sorry about that.
你不吃午饭吗
You don't eat lunch?
我在午饭后有场戏要拍
I've got a scene after lunch.
是吗
Yeah?
在拍戏前吃午饭会让我行动迟缓
Eating lunch before I do a scene makes me sluggish.
我相信这是演员的职责...
I believe it's the job of an actor...
而且我用"男演员"而不是"女演员"
And I say "Actor," Not "Actress,"
因为"女演员"这个词毫无意义
because the word "Actress" is nonsensical.
避免表演时出状况是演员的职责
It's the actor's job to avoid impediments to their performance.
发挥出最佳水平也是演员的职责
It's the actor's job to strive for 100 percent effectiveness.
当然我们不可能成功  但对成功的追求
Naturally, we never succeed, but it's the pursuit...
还是有意义的
that's meaningful.
-你是谁  -你可以叫我玛拉贝拉
- Who are you? - You can call me Marabella.
玛拉贝拉  姓什么
Mar... Marabella what?
玛拉贝拉·兰瑟
Marabella Lancer.
不  不  别这样  你的真名是什么
No, no, come on, come on. What's your real name?
在拍摄时  我更喜欢人们
When we're on set, I'd prefer to only
用角色的名字称呼我
be referred to by my character's name.
这样能帮我入戏
It helps me invest in the reality of the story.
我两种都试过  叫我角色名
I've tried it both ways, and I'm always just
总会让我表现稍微好点
a tiny bit better when I don't break character.
哪怕只是好一点点  我都愿意去做
And if I can be a tiny bit better, I want to be.
你是那个反派  卡勒布·德卡图
You're the bad guy. Caleb DeCoteau.
我以为应该念卡勒布·德科塔
I thought it was pronounced Caleb "Dakota."
我很肯定是德卡图
I'm pretty sure it's "DeCoteau."
德卡图
DeCoteau.
德卡图  德卡图
DeCoteau. DeCoteau.
你在看什么书
What are you reading?
华特·迪士尼的传记
It's a biography on Walt Disney.
很精彩
It's fascinating.
他是个天才
He's a genius, you know.
那种50年100年才出一个的天才
I mean, a once-in-every-50 -or-100-years kind of genius.
你多大  12岁
What are you, 12?
我8岁
I'm 8.
你在看什么书
What are you reading?
就是本西部小说
Just a Western.
那是什么书  好看吗
What does that mean? Is it good?
-很好看  -讲的什么故事
- Pretty good. - What's the story?
我还没看完呢
I haven't finished it yet.
我没问你完整的故事情节
I didn't ask for the whole story.
大概讲什么的
What's the idea of the story?
好吧
Well... ahem,
故事的主角是位驯马牛仔
it's about this guy who's a bronco buster.
就是讲他的生活经历
It's the story of his life.
这家伙叫汤姆·布里兹
Guy's name is Tom Breezy,
但人人都叫他轻风[布里兹音同微风]
but everyone always calls him Easy Breezy.
轻风20来岁时
Now, when Easy Breezy was in his 20s
年轻帅气  他能...
and-and-and young and good-looking, he could...
你随便扔给他什么马  他都能驯服
He could break any horse that you could throw at him.
那时  他春风得意
Back then, he just had a way.
他快40岁时
Now he's into his, uh, late 30s
重重地摔了一跤  摔伤了屁股
and he takes a bad fall, and it messes up his hip.
他并没有  没有瘸
He's not... He's not... He's not crippled
或者残废  但...
or anything like that, but...
他的脊椎出了大毛病
But he's got spine problems he never had before, and he spends, uh...
大多数时间他都比以前要痛苦得多
more of his days in pain than he ever did before.
天哪  这本小说听上去不错
Jeepers, this sounds like a good novel.
对  还行
Yeah, it's not bad.
你看到哪里了
Where are you in it?
大概看了一半
Mm. About midway.
那轻风现在怎么样了
What's happening to Easy Breezy now?
他...
Uh, he's, um... He...
他已经不复当年了
He's not the best anymore.
老实说  差远了  而且...
In fact, far from it. And...
他逐步向生活妥协  结果...
he's coming to terms with what it's like to be slightly more...
却...
use...
却一天比一天更没用
Slightly more useless each day.
没事的  卡勒布
I-it's okay, Caleb.
没事的
It's okay.
听起来这是本很伤感的书
It sounds like a really sad book.
可怜的轻风
Poor Easy Breezy.
我都要哭了  虽然我根本没看过这本书
I'm practically crying, and I haven't even read it.
15年后你也会这样
About 15 years, you'll be living it.
什么
What?
没什么  小可爱  我只是...
Nothing, pumpkin puss. I'm just...
逗你玩呢
I'm just teasing you.
你知道吗  你
You know something? You...
你对这本书的看法可能是对的
You might be right about this book.
它对我的触动比我想象的更深
I think it hits harder than I gave it credit for.
我不喜欢"小可爱"这种名字
I don't like names like "Pumpkin puss,"
但既然你不开心
but since you're upset,
我们以后再说这个
we'll talk about that some other time.
我只到西木区
I'm only going as far as Westwood Village.
乞丐可没得选
Hey, beggars can't be choosers.
-上来吧  -谢谢
- Come on in. - Thanks.
-非常感谢  -不客气
- Thank you so much. - My pleasure.
-祝你一路好运  -谢谢
- Good luck on your adventure. - Thank you.
-在大苏尔玩的开心  -非常感谢
- Have a good time in Big Sur. - Thank you so much.
-保重  -你也是
- Take care. - You too.
乔治·佩帕德
《红杏出墙案外案》
珍·茜宝  理查德·基利
《破坏部队》
艾尔克·萨默  莎伦·塔特 关南施
奈杰尔·格林  蒂娜·露易丝
-你好  -你好
- Oh, hey. - Hello.
有什么可以效劳吗  女士
How can I help you, young lady?
我来拿我预定的
I'm here to pick up a first edition
托马斯·哈代的《德伯家的苔丝》第一版
of Thomas Hardy's Tess of the d'Urbervilles I ordered.
用波兰斯基的名字订的
It's under Polanski.
对  我知道哪本
Yeah, you're talking books there, kid.
就是说啊  这本书很好看的
Oh, I know. Isn't it wonderful?
-当然了  -我刚看完
- Yeah. Oh, man. - I just read it.
我要买一本作为礼物送给我丈夫
I'm getting it as a gift for my husband.
-瑞克·道尔顿  -就是我
- Rick Dalton? - You bet.
我是吉姆·斯泰西  这是我的剧  欢迎加入
Jim Stacy. This is my show. Welcome aboard.
我们真的很高兴能有像你这专业的演员
We're real glad to have a pro like you
在试播集饰演反派
playing the heavy on the pilot.
而且我要告诉你  我就差一点点
And I gotta tell you, I came damn close
就加入《麦克拉斯基的十四拳》了
to being in The Fourteen Fists of McCluskey.
-没开玩笑  -是的
- No kidding. - Yeah.
告诉你  我...
Let me tell you, I...
我拿到这个角色纯粹靠运气
I just got my part-part by sheer luck.
直到开拍前两周
Up until two weeks before shooting,
这个角色还是费比安的
Fabian was in the part.
然后他在拍《弗吉尼亚人》时伤了肩膀
Then-then he breaks his shoulder doing a Virginian.
这个角色就是我的了  所以...
That's how I got it, so...
瑞克  问你点我听说的事
Hey, Rick, I gotta ask you something I heard about.
你差点就拿到了
Was it true you almost
麦奎因在《大逃亡》里的那个角色  是真的吗
got the McQueen part in The Great Escape?
-希尔兹  对吗  -其实是叫希尔兹上尉
- Hilts, isn't it? - Captain Hilts, actually.
-试图逃跑了十七次  -是十八次
- Seventeen escape attempts. - Eighteen.
没试过镜  没开过会
Never had an audition. Never had a meeting.
也没见过约翰·斯特奇斯[大逃亡导演]
Never met John Sturges.
所以  我觉得我没有...
So, no, I don't think you could say I...
差点拿到了那个角色  但...
I almost got the part, but...
-隧道工  工程师  -飞人
- Tunnel man, engineer. - Flier.
按美军的叫法  是前途无量的飞行员
I suppose what's called in the American Army, a hotshot pilot.
但其实有一小段时间
But the story goes, for a brief moment,
麦奎因差点不想拍这个电影
McQueen almost passed on the movie,
就在那一小段时间里
and during that brief moment,
我显然已经进了四位候选人名单
I, apparently, was on a list of four.
你有其他计划吗
You have other plans?
我还没见过柏林
I haven't seen Berlin yet
不管是从地面还是从天上
from the ground or from the air,
我计划在战争结束前两种方法都试一次
and I plan on doing both before the war's over.
你还有谁
You and who?
-跟那三个乔治  -哪三个乔治
- Me and... Me and three Georges. - Which three Georges?
佩帕德  马海尔斯和查金斯
Peppard, Maharis and Chakiris.
-天哪兄弟  -对
- Oh, man. - Yeah.
没演这部戏一定很痛苦
That's gotta hurt.
对  但我还是没演成
Yeah, well, I didn't get it,
麦奎因演了
McQueen did it,
而且说实话  我根本就没机会
and, frankly, I never had a chance.
十天禁闭  希尔兹
Ten days isolation, Hilts.
是希尔兹上尉
Captain Hilts.
那就二十天禁闭
Twenty days.
好吧
Right.
我出来的时候你还会在这里吗
Oh, you'll still be here when I get out?
滚去牢房
Cooler.
《破坏部队》
-请给我一张票  -七毛五
- One, please. - Seventy-five cents.
如果那部电影里有我呢
What if I'm in the movie?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我是说  我参演了那部电影
I mean, I'm in the movie.
我是莎伦·塔特
I'm Sharon Tate.
这是你演的吗
You're in this?
我演卡尔森小姐  那个马大哈
I play Miss Carlson, the klutz.
那就是我
That's me.
但那是《娃娃谷》里那姑娘
But that's the girl from Valley of the Dolls.
那就是我  《娃娃谷》里那姑娘
Well, that's me, the girl from Valley of the Dolls.
真的吗
Really?
真的
Really.
鲁宾  出来
Hey, Rubin! Come out here.
这是《娃娃谷》里那姑娘
This is the girl from Valley of the Dolls.
-帕蒂·杜克吗  -不  另外一个
- Patty Duke? - No, the other one.
-《冷暖人间》里的吗  -不  另外一个
- The girl from Peyton Place? - No, the other one.
最后去拍色情片的那个
The one who ends up doing dirty movies.
-哦  -她演了这部电影
- Oh. - She's in this movie.
-哦  -我叫莎伦·塔特
- Oh. - Sharon Tate.
欢迎来到布鲁因  塔特小姐
Well, welcome to the Bruin, Miss Tate.
谢谢你光临我们剧院
Thank you for coming to our theater.
你要进来看这部电影吗
Would you like to come in and see the show?
我可以吗
Could I?
当然可以
By all means.
谢谢
Thank you.
我能拍张照片吗
Hey, can I get a picture?
当然
Oh, sure.
你何不站在那个海报旁边
You know, why don't you stand over by the poster
让别人知道你是谁
so people will know who you are.
好  帮我拿一下
Okay. Could you?
要来点零食吗
Would you like some refreshments?
-不用了  谢谢  -好好欣赏电影吧
- Oh, I'm fine. Thank you. - Enjoy the show.
能问你个私人问题吗
Can I ask you a personal question?
-求之不得  -你这样的乖乖仔
- I wish you would. - How did a nice boy
怎么会加入这样的乐队
like you get involved with a group like the Heads?
我被美国革命女儿会拒绝后
I turned to them after I was rejected by
就加入他们了
the Daughters of the American Revolution.
这酒店很不错
Very pleasant hotel here.
-赫尔姆先生  -什么事
- Mr. Helm? - Yes?
我叫弗雷娅
I'm Freya.
欢迎来到丹麦  赫尔姆先生
Welcome to Denmark, Mr. Helm.
这些是给你的  街道地图  还有名胜古迹
These are for you. Street maps, places of interest.
这个也是给你的
This is for you too.
-这是哪年的  -1949年
- What year was that? - 1949.
那是个好年份
That's a very good year.
我是来尽力帮你的
I'm here to help any way I can.
你真好
It's very nice of you.
有什么我能效劳的吗
Is there anything you'd like me to do?
-是的  有几件事  -是  先生
- Yes, a couple things. - Yes, sir.
你能别压着我的摄影机箱子吗  拜托
Would you mind getting off my camera case, please?
-对不起  -没关系
- Oh, I'm sorry. - Oh, that's all right.
- I'm so sorry. - That's okay.
我很抱歉...
I'm sorry about...
欢迎来到丹麦
Welcome to Denmark.
你这酒店不一般啊
This is some kind of hotel you've got here.
半瓶水总比没有强
Half a bottle is better than none.
早  伙计
Morning, partner.
我下次再来看你
Probably come by to see you later.
别靠近了  白痴
That's far enough, jughead.
我不叫白痴
Name's not jughead.
你在这里干什么  小子
What you doing around here, boy?
我口渴了  那是家酒吧  对吗
I'm thirsty. That's a saloon, ain't it?
没错  那是家酒吧
Oh, yeah, that's a saloon.
-只是你不能进去  -吉尔伯特先生
- Only you can't come in. - Mr. Gilbert.
别让我妨碍你赚钱
Don't let me stop you from earning your money.
我知道你没有玉米粉蒸肉
I know how bored and restless you get
会有多无聊烦躁
when you run out of tamales.
吉尔伯特先生  如果我是你
But, Mr. Gilbert, if I was you,
我就去查出那个白痴的名字
I'd find out that jughead's name.
让我来介绍一下你们二位吧
Allow me to introduce the two of you.
这边这位是鲍勃·吉尔伯特
This here is Bob Gilbert.
那个商人吗
The Businessman?
没错
That's right.
商人鲍勃·吉尔伯特
Business Bob Gilbert.
他又是谁  卡勒布
And who might he be, Caleb?
那位伙计叫马德里
Well, that's a fella by the name of Madrid.
约翰尼·马德里
Johnny Madrid.
约翰尼·马德里又是谁
Who's Johnny Madrid?
他不是这里的人
He ain't from round here.
是吗
No, really.
他什么来头  卡勒布
Who is he, Caleb?
你马上就会知道了
Oh, you're about to find out...
商人
Businessman.
酒吧
你准备好了就开始  吉尔伯特
Ready when you are, Gilbert.
约翰尼·马德里
Johnny Madrid.
我们多久没见了
How long has it been?
自上次在华雷斯一别  得有三年了
Since that time in Juárez, about three years ago.
快进来喝一杯
Well, come on in and have a drink.
这样的话...
Hell, in that case...
我请你吧  卡勒布
buy you a drink, Caleb?
没问题  约翰尼
Sure, Johnny.
喝梅斯卡尔酒怎么样
How about some mezcal?
就跟在华雷斯那次一样
Like that time in Juárez.
那天死了不少人
A lot of people died that day.
是啊
Yes, they did.
但我们玩得很开心
But we had a good time.
不是吗
Didn't we?
没错
Yeah, we did.
你先请  德卡图
After you, DeCoteau.
佩佩  到吧台来  我有客人
Pepe! Get your behind behind that bar. I have a guest.
豆子怎么样
How's the beans?
还凑合
I've had worse.
一美金
One dollar.
敬我的妻子  和我所有的宝贝
To my wife and all my sweethearts.
愿她们永不相见
May they never meet.
马德里先生  来我这桌吧
Senor Madrid, you care to join me at my table
这是我招待客人的地方
where I entertain my guests?
我很乐意  德卡图先生
I'd be delighted, Monsieur DeCoteau.
带上酒瓶一起
Take the bottle with you.
约翰尼...
So, Johnny...
什么风把你吹到阿罗约德尔奥罗来了
what brings you to Arroyo del Oro?
你知道我的  卡勒布
Oh, you know me, Caleb.
为了钱
Money.
那谁付钱呢
And who's paying around here?
希望是你
I hope you.
你又听说了我什么事
And what have you heard about me?
我听说了兰瑟牧场的事
I heard about the Lancer Ranch.
你私占的那一大群牛
All the cattle you've appropriated.
还有一大块地  许多头奶牛  一大笔钱
A lot of land, a lot of cows, a lot of money,
毫无王法可言
no law to speak of,
只有一个老头
and nothing but an old man
和一群墨西哥牧场工守着
and some Mexican ranch hands to shoo you off.
你那个惹火的女儿呢  会拉小提琴那个
Say, where's that chili pepper daughter of yours with the fiddle?
睡着了
She's asleep.
叫醒她  让她下来
Wake her the heck up, get her down here
带上小提琴和琴弓  给客人露一手
with her fiddle and her bow, and entertain my guest.
好的  先生  但拜托这次别伤害她
Si, senor. But, please, don't hurt her this time.
我不会伤害她
I ain't gonna hurt her.
只想让她拉提琴
I just want her to play the fiddle.
台词  "叫她来  告诉她"什么来着
The line? "Go... Go fetch her and tell her" What?
"叫她来  告诉她
"Go fetch her and tell her
我会给她整整五美金"
I'll give her a fat $5 gold piece..."
没错  叫她来  告诉她
Right. Go fetch her and tell her
我会给她整整五美金
I'll give her a fat-fat $5 gold piece,
让她带着火辣的感情拉提琴  没说错吧
she play her little chili pepper heart out, right?
-没错  -知道了
- Right. - Got it.
我不会伤害她
I ain't gonna hurt her.
我只想让她拉小提琴
I just want her to play the fiddle.
快去叫她来  告诉她
Now, go fetch her and tell her
我会给她整整五美金
I'll give her a fat $5 gold piece,
让她带着火辣的感情拉提琴
she play her little chili pepper heart out.
赶紧去
Go on.
约翰尼
So, Johnny,
你还听说了些什么
what else you heard?
我听说你把兰瑟逼得很紧
I heard you're pushing Lancer pretty hard,
但兰瑟很有钱
but Lancer's got money.
他总有一天
At some point,
会雇人报仇的
he's gonna hire some guns and push back.
-台词  台词  -"说不定他已经这么做了"
- Line. Line. Line, line, line. - "Maybe he already has."
说不定...我操
Maybe... Goddamn it!
我把整条都给毁了  山姆
I fucked this whole thing up, Sam.
-我演砸了  -别停啊  坚持
- I fucked this whole thing up. - Keep going! Fight through it.
能重拍这条吗  能暂停一下吗
Can we just go back? Please, can we just cut?
别啊  你把台词说完就行了
No, really, just say the fucking line!
说真的  山姆  拜托了
No, really, Sam, please.
-"说不定他已经这么做了"  -好吧好吧
- "Maybe he already has." - All right!
-"说不定他已经这么做了"  -行了  我去
- "Maybe he already has!" - All right, goddamn it!
行  我说
All right, all right!
你可是亡命之徒  瑞克  快打起精神
You're a goddamn outlaw, Rick. Come on, now.
我可以  我能行
I got it. I got it.
我们退回去一点行吗
Go back a bit, would you?
他说得没错  回到原机位
No, he's right. Back to one.
-好了  现在集中精力  -我会的
- Okay, now, use all that, baby. - I'm gonna use it.
-我一定集中精力  -找回状态  全神贯注
- Oh, I'm gonna use it. - Use it all. Put it all inside.
我会的
I'm gonna use it.
准备...
And...
开拍
action.
我听说你把兰瑟逼得很紧
I heard you're pushing Lancer pretty hard,
但兰瑟很有钱
but Lancer's got money.
他总有一天
At some point,
会雇人报仇的
he's gonna hire some guns and push back.
说不定他已经这么做了
Maybe he already has.
或许吧
Maybe.
也许是我不喜欢兰瑟
Maybe I don't like Lancer.
不喜欢他脚上的靴子
Maybe I don't like his boots.
也不喜欢他穿着靴子
Maybe I don't like the way
践踏别人的那副样子
he uses those boots to step on people.
我他妈刚才是怎么回事
What the fuck was that?!
老天啊
Jesus Christ!
我操
Fuck!
废物
Piece of shit.
我去你的  瑞克  我对天发誓
Fucking damn it, Rick, I swear to God.
居然记不住台词  让自己
Forgot your fucking lines, embarrassed yourself
在那么多人面前难堪
like that in front of all those goddamn people!
喝了一晚上的酒  又管不住了
You were drinking all night, fucking drinking again,
整整八杯威士忌
eight goddamn fucking whiskey sours.
我在搞毛啊
Fucking bullshit.
你就是个可悲的酒鬼
You're a fucking miserable drunk.
居然连台词都记不住
Not fucking remembering your fucking lines.
我明明背过台词
I practiced them,
但现在就跟完全没准备过一样
and now I don't look like I goddamn practiced them!
傻坐在片场的样子就像只狒狒
You're sitting there like a fucking baboon!
操  八杯威士忌
Fuck! Eight fucking whiskey sours.
喝了三四杯还不知道收手  居然还喝了八杯
I couldn't stop at fucking three or four. I have eight!
为什么啊  你就是个酒鬼
Why?! You're a fucking alcoholic.
就这么喜欢喝吗
You fucking drink too much, huh?
每晚如此  每晚都他妈的如此
Every fucking night. Every fucking night.
行了  我受够了
That's it, that's fucking it!
必须做出行动了
That's fucking it.
现在就开始戒酒  听到了吗
You stop drinking right now, all right?
对自己发誓
Make a promise to yourself.
马上戒酒
You're gonna stop fucking drinking.
不管了
Oh, fuck it.
操
Damn it!
你要证明给那个小屁孩看
You show that little fucking girl.
证明给那个吉姆·斯泰西看
You're gonna show that goddamn Jim Stacy.
在该死的片场向所有人证明
You're gonna show them on that goddamn fucking set
他妈的瑞克·道尔顿到底是谁
who the fuck Rick Dalton is, all right?
我跟你说件事
Let me tell you something.
你要是不把台词说对
You don't get these lines right,
我今天晚上就一枪爆了你的头
I'm gonna blow your fucking brains out tonight.
听到了吗
All right?
你的脑花会溅满整个游泳池
Your brains are gonna be splattered all over your goddamn pool.
我说真的  傻逼
I mean it, motherfucker.
赶紧振作起来
Get your shit together.
-好些了吗  好  -非常棒
- Better? Okay. - It's great.
我去
Shit.
去你妈的  臭警察
Fuck you, you fucking pig!
不是吧
Oh, no.
你好啊  辣妹
Hello, hot stuff.
看来事不过三啊
Looks like third time's the charm.
腌菜好吃吗
Mm. How were those pickles?
特别好吃
Real good.
我那都是高档货
They were the fancy kind.
要载我一程吗
Give me a lift?
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
我要去查茨沃斯
I'm going to Chatsworth.
查茨沃斯
Chatsworth?
你成天在伯班克大道上溜达
You hitch up and down Burbank Boulevard all day
就是为了找人顺路载你去查茨沃斯
till someone says they'll drive you to Chatsworth?
游客们最喜欢开车送我了
Tourists love to drive me.
我可是他们在洛杉矶度假最喜欢的环节
I'm their favorite part of their L.A. Vacation.
估计他们下半辈子都会津津乐道
They'll be telling stories about the Hollywood hippie girl
曾经载过一位好莱坞嬉皮女
that they gave a ride to the movie ranch
去电影牧场的故事了
for the rest of their lives.
等等  斯潘电影牧场吗
Wait, Spahn Movie Ranch?
-没错  -你要去斯潘电影牧场
- Yeah. - That's where you're going? Spahn Movie Ranch?
你去那里干什么
Why you going there?
我住那里
I live there.
-独居吗  -不是
- Alone? - No.
我和我朋友
Me and my friends.
所以你和一群跟你一样的朋友
So you and a bunch of friends like you
都住在斯潘电影牧场
all live at Spahn Movie Ranch?
对
Yeah.
上车吧  我送你去那里
Well, hop in. I'll take you there.
太好了
Great!
《乔治·普特南新闻秀》
走这里  然后上好莱坞高速
Go down here and get on the Hollywood Freeway.
我知道怎么走
I know where it is.
你是以前经常在那里拍电影的老牛仔吗
Are you some old cowboy guy that used to make movies there?
怎么
What?
我只是惊讶
I'm just surprised how accurate
你居然能把我描述得这么准确
that description of me really is.
以前经常在斯潘牧场拍电影的老牛仔
Some old cowboy guy that used to shoot movies at Spahn Ranch.
这么说你以前
So you used to make Westerns at the ranch
就经常拍西部片吗
back in the old-timey days?
如果你的"以前"
Well, if by "The old-timey days,"
是指八年前的电视业的话  没错
you mean television eight years ago, yeah.
你是演员吗
Are you an actor?
我是特技替身
No, I'm a stuntman.
你是替身啊
You're a stuntman.
这样就好多了
That's way better.
为什么好多了
Why is that way better?
演员都特别假
Actors are phony.
他们不过是说几句别人写的台词
They just say lines that other people write
然后在白痴电视剧里假装杀人罢了
and pretend to murder people on their stupid TV shows.
与此同时呢  每天都有活生生的人在越南丧命
Meanwhile, real people are being murdered every day in Vietnam.
想边开车边让我口吗
Want me to suck your cock while driving?
你多大了
How old are you?
什么
What?
你多少岁了
How old are you?
天呐
Wow, man.
好久都没人问我这个问题了
That's the first time anybody asked that in a long time.
回答我
What's the answer?
好吧  是要玩什么儿童游戏吗
Okay. We gonna play kiddie games?
我十八  舒服了吗
Eighteen. Feel better?
你有身份证明吗
You got some ID, you know,
比如驾照什么的
like a driver's license or something?
-你在开玩笑吧  -我没有
- Are you joking? - No, I'm not.
我需要看到证件证明你十八岁了
I need to see something official that verifies that you're 18,
你当然没有了  因为你根本就没成年
which you don't have because you're not.
要说谁最会扫兴  老兄
Talk about a bring-down bummer, dude.
那肯定是你
That's you.
是吗
Yeah.
显然  我还没小到不能跟你上床
Obviously, I'm not too young to fuck you.
但是呢  你已经老到干不动我了
But obviously, you are too old to fuck me.
我真正老到不能干的是  因为上床而进监狱
What I'm too old to do is go to jail for poontang.
我这一辈子都在躲避牢狱之灾
Prison's been trying to get me all my life.
现在我还没有进去
It ain't got me yet.
如果有一天进去了
The day it does,
也不能是因为你
it won't be because of you.
别介意哈
No offense.
你还好吗  亲爱的
You all right, honey?
她很好  对吧  小不点
She's just fine, ain't you, shorty?
我没事  斯科特
I'm fine, Scott.
他们没伤害你吧
They haven't hurt you?
摄像机准备好了  道尔顿先生
Camera's ready, Mr. Dalton.
我马上出来
I'll be right out.
战争
The war.
我和英国陆军一起去了印...
I rode with the British cavalry in Indi...
各就各位  大伙儿  五秒后开拍
Stand by, guys. We're going in five.
兰瑟的人来了
Lancer's boys are here!
那老家伙来了
The old man here?
不是
Nada.
但他儿子来了
But the son is.
波士顿的那个
The one from Boston.
我不知道
I don't know.
你是波士顿的吗
You from Boston?
是
Yes.
是波士顿的那儿子
It's the Boston one!
让其他人在外面等着
Keep the others outside.
让那兄弟进来
Let the brother come in.
你听到他说的了  波士顿小子
You heard him, Boston.
进来吧  波士顿小子
Come on in, Boston.
你瞧  亲爱的
See, honey?
我说了他们会来谈判的
I told you they'd come to parlay.
你还好吗  亲爱的
You all right, honey?
她很好
Oh, she's just fine.
对吧  小不点
Ain't you, shorty?
我没事  斯科特
I'm fine, Scott.
他们没伤害你吧
They haven't hurt you?
暂时没有
Not yet, I ain't.
但一切都可能改变
But that can all change...
弹指一挥间
like that.
告诉我
Say...
你那瘸腿是怎么回事
where'd you get that limp?
打仗时留下的
From the war.
你是哪一方
Which side?
我和英国陆军一起去了印度
I rode with the British cavalry in India.
他们管那身行头叫什么
What'd they call that outfit?
孟加拉骑兵
Bengal Lancers.
这可真逗乐
Now, now, now, that is funny.
-真好笑  -这不好笑
- That is funny. - That's not so funny.
你没听懂吗
Don't you get it?
"孟加拉兰瑟"
"Bengal Lancer"?
对哦
Oh, yeah.
现在我懂了
I get it now.
-是挺好笑的  -没错
- That is kind of funny. - It is.
你知道绑架会被判绞刑
You do know kidnapping is a hanging offense.
一枪崩了这小妮子也是
So is blowing the heads off little girls.
但他们没法绞死我两回  对吧
But they can only hang me once, right?
那么
So...
你过来是为了
you come down here for a...
波士顿式的闲聊
For a Boston social?
-还是我们谈谈价格  -多少钱
- Or we gonna talk price? - How much?
我想五万美元能让我
I'd say $50,000 would buy me
在墨西哥买不少魔力鸡了
a whole lot of chicken mole in Mexico.
那可是一大笔钱
That's a lot of money.
这小妮子值这一大笔钱
Well, she's a lot of little girl.
你不同意吗
Or don't you agree?
我同意
I agree.
那接下去怎么办
So, what's next?
我会派人到你们的牧场
Well, I'll send one of my boys out to your ranch
告诉你们细节  但是
to fill you in on all the details, but, uh...
有一个事我现在就可以告诉你
the one detail I'm gonna fill you in on right now is this:
我可不要随便哪个墨西哥牛仔
I don't want no beaner bronco buster
给我送来五万美金
handing me that $50,000.
我要让那老家伙自己送来
I want the old man himself.
默多克·兰瑟亲自把五万美金放我大腿上
Murdoch Lancer puts $50,000 in my lap...
否则这小妮子就玩完
or I heave this little pitcher down a well!
明白了吗  波士顿小子
You got that, Boston?
明白
Yeah.
行了  传话小子
All right, messenger boy.
传话去吧
Deliver my message.
让邪恶来临吧  性感的哈姆雷特
Give me evil, sexy Hamlet.
沉沦其中
Settle into it.
享受其中
Enjoy it.
剪
And cut!
天哪
Oh, boy.
我没伤到你吧  玛拉贝拉
I didn't hurt you there, Marabella,
-刚才那一推  -不不  我没事
- with that throw, did I? - No, no, no. I'm good.
我这有垫子呢
I got pads on.
而且我经常自己故意摔倒
And I throw myself on the floor
就为了好玩  就算没人付我工钱
just for fun, even when I'm not getting paid.
大门可以了
The gate's clean.
瑞克  瑞克  瑞克
Rick, Rick, Rick.
把她摔出去
Put her there.
-就是我想要的效果  -真的吗
- That was it. - Really?
简直太精彩了
That was absolutely fantastic.
-谢谢  -我太喜欢了
- Oh, thank you. - I loved it.
你把小女孩往地上一摔
Your idea about throwing the little girl
这想法简直是神来之笔
on the ground just worked like a charm.
-我想着你说了莎士比亚  -对
- I figured you said Shakespeare, so... - Yeah.
就是这样  那简直
That's right. That was...
那正是我说的"给我个惊喜"的意思
That's what I mean by "Scare me."
-对对对  -邪恶的哈姆雷特会使人害怕
- Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. - Evil Hamlet scares people.
-没错  -对了
- All right. - Oh, and by the way...
-"墨西哥牛仔"  -嗯
- "Beaner bronco buster"? - Yeah.
你是从哪想到这么说的
Where the hell did that come from?
-我不知道  就是即兴  -妙极了
- I don't know. Improv. - That was wonderful.
简直了不起  押了三个头韵
It was just... That was a triple alliterative improv.
这可不常听到
You don't hear those too often.
-好吗  没问题了  -好  我们不需要
- Okay? We're good. - All right. We don't...?
-不要再拍一条吗  -完事了
- Don't need to go again? - No. We're done.
-上一条很完美  -好的
- That was fantastic. - All right.
好  下一场  拍妓院那场戏
Okay, moving on. We're in the bordello.
下一幕片场
Next setup!
这是我这辈子见过最完美的演绎
That was the best acting I've ever seen in my whole life.
谢谢
Thank you.
好一个瑞克·道尔顿
Rick fucking Dalton.
有车来了
That's a car.
好奇怪的车
That's a strange car.
蛇妹  去看看外面是谁
Snake, go see who's outside.
是谁
So who is it?
还不确定
I ain't for sure yet.
亮黄色的轿跑
It's a bitchen yellow Coupe de Ville.
盯着他
Keep an eye on him.
来吧
Come on.
大伙都去哪了
Where the hell is everybody?
吉卜赛呢
Hey, where's Gypsy?
她在拆车的地儿
She's down by the chop shop.
斯潘电影牧场
-嗨  -你好
- Hey! - Hello!
吉卜赛  来见见我的新朋友
Gypsy! I want you to come meet my new friend.
一个穿着夏威夷衬衫的老家伙
Some old-looking dude in a Hawaiian shirt
刚送小猫回来
who just gave Pussycat a ride home.
他只是送她回来
He just gave her a lift?
不  她正带他到处转  认识大伙
Nope. She's bringing him down the ranch to meet everybody.
在门边上看着  如果他往这边走就告诉我
Stay by the door. Tell me if he starts coming this way.
-欢迎来到我们的公社  -谢谢邀请
- Welcome to our community. - Thanks for having me.
谢谢你送我们可爱的小猫回家
Thank you for giving our precious Pussy a ride home.
别客气
Think nothing of it.
我们都爱小猫
We love Pussy.
没错
Yes, we do.
大家都去哪儿了  孩子们呢
Hey, where is everybody? Where's the children?
大家都去圣巴巴拉了
Everybody left for Santa Barbara.
真的吗
Really?
查理也走了  大家都不在
Charlie's gone? Everybody left?
也不是所有人  但大部分人都走了
Well, not "Everybody" everybody, but mostly everybody.
真扫兴
Drag.
我还希望克利夫能见见查理呢
I really wanted Cliff to meet Charlie.
我觉得查理会喜欢你
I think Charlie's really gonna dig you.
-安吉  等等  -那下回吧
- Angel, hold up. - Well, maybe next time.
嗯  你得再来噢
Yeah, you got to come back.
-好吗  -好  一定
- Yeah? - Yeah, sure.
和你的光辉岁月比起来如何
So how's it all comparing to your glory days?
时过境迁了
Well, things have changed.
上马背很轻巧啊  康妮
Not a bad mount, Connie.
我以前在田纳西天天骑马
I used to ride horses every day back in Tennessee.
-是吗  -每天
- Is that right? - Every day?
每周
Well, every week.
真不错
All right.
她真是个可人儿
Ain't she just darling?
我叫露露
So, uh, my name is Lulu.
这是泰克斯
This is Tex.
我们将带你们进行一场山间小道骑行
We're gonna be leading you on a great trail ride
穿越美丽的圣苏珊娜峡谷
through the beautiful Santa Susana canyons.
柯特  我知道你是位颇有经验的骑手
Now, Curt, I hear you're already an experienced rider.
-对  -你也是吗  康妮
- Yes. - Yeah, so are you, Connie?
-没错  -泰克斯  过来一下
- Yes, I am. - Hey, Tex? Come here.
那如果你们两位都有经验
So, uh, if you're both experienced riders,
那这次骑行就是纯粹享乐了
I guess we'll just make this ride about having fun.
你们准备好享乐了吗
You ready to have some fun?
小猫带了个男人回来
So Pussycat brought back some guy with her.
吉卜赛想让你去看看
Gypsy wants you to go give him a look-see.
好  没问题
Yeah. Sure thing.
对了  这位你一定要认识认识
Oh, and here's someone you absolutely have to meet.
最受宠爱的儿子之一
One of our most favorite sons.
泰克斯  过来和克利夫打个招呼
Tex, come on over here and say hi to Cliff.
-你好吗  克利夫  -泰克斯
- Howdy, Cliff. - Tex.
-你来自得州哪儿  -你肯定不知道的小地方
- What part of Texas you from? - Oh, a place you never heard of.
科普维尔
Copeville.
去过休斯顿吗
Ah. Ever been to Houston?
当然
Course I have.
嗯  我之前在休斯顿的带镣囚犯队待过两周
Yeah, I spent two weeks once on a Houston chain gang.
八月份  可不是闹着玩的
In August, no less.
听上去可不好玩
That doesn't sound like a whole lot of fun.
以后我可不敢再打碎条子的下巴了
It's the last cop's jaw I ever broke, I can tell you that.
哥们
Man...
查理肯定会喜欢你
Charlie's gonna dig you.
那个夏威夷家伙看起来没问题
The Hawaiian guy seems to be okay.
大家说话都很客气
Everybody's talking all friendly.
-祝你日安  -谢谢
- Enjoy your day! - Thank you.
泰克斯掂量过他了  现在他骑走了
Tex checked him out, and now he's riding away.
如果他往这边来  告诉我
If he comes this way, let me know.
乔治·斯潘还是这个牧场的主人吗
Hey, does George Spahn still own this ranch?
没错  乔治还是主人
Yeah, George still owns it.
-他还住这儿吗  -对
- Does he still live here? - Yeah.
他还住在那栋房子里吗
Does he still live right there?
没错
Yeah.
他现在在吗
Is he here now?
我想在吧
I guess so.
所以乔治允许你们所有人住在这
So George gave you all permission to be here?
当然了
Course he did.
你们照顾他吗
And y'all take care of him?
我们把乔治照顾得好好的
Oh, we take care of George.
我们爱乔治
We love George.
那我能不能
Well, is there anything wrong
过去跟老朋友打个招呼
with me saying hello to an old friend?
你现在不能见他
You can't see him right now.
为什么我现在不能见他
Why can't I see him right now?
因为他在睡午觉
Because he's napping.
现在是他睡午觉的时间
This is his nap time.
我就自己去看看吧
Well, I think I'll just go see for myself.
谁知道呢
You never know.
他说不定刚醒来
He might have just woke up.
那夏威夷老家伙往这边过来了
The old Hawaiian guy's coming this way.
好  你们都走开
Okay, y'all, beat it.
我来对付这家伙
I'll handle this guy.
行吧
Fine.
你就是熊妈妈吗
You the mama bear?
-我能帮你吗  -希望能
- Can I help you? - I hope so.
我是乔治的老朋友  想着过来打个招呼
I'm an old friend of George's. Thought I'd stop and say hello.
你真是太客气了
That's very nice of you,
但现在时机不凑巧
but you picked the wrong time.
乔治现在正在睡午觉
George is taking a nap right now.
那太不幸了
Oh, that is unfortunate.
对  没错
Yes, it is.
-你叫什么  -克利夫·布思
- What's your name? - Cliff Booth.
你怎么认识乔治的
How do you know George?
我以前在这牧场拍过西部片
I used to shoot Westerns here at the ranch.
你上回见乔治是什么时候了
When was the last time you saw George?
我想大概是
Oh, I'd say about...
八年前了
eight years ago.
真抱歉
Oh. I'm sorry.
我不知道你俩关系这么好
I didn't realize the two of you were so close.
他醒来后
When he wakes up,
我会告诉他你来过
I'll let him know you came by.
我真的很希望自己去打个招呼
I'd really like to say a quick hello now
趁着我还在这
while I'm here.
毕竟长途跋涉
Came a long ways.
我不知道什么时候还会再回来
Don't know when I'll get back this way again.
我理解  但恐怕那不可能
Oh, I understand, but I'm afraid that's impossible.
不可能
Impossible?
为什么不可能
Why is that impossible?
因为我和乔治喜欢周日晚上看电视
Because me and George like to watch TV on Sunday night...
《联邦调查局》和《伯南扎的牛仔》
F.B.I. and Bonanza.
但是乔治总是睡着  所以我让他睡午觉
...but George finds it hard to keep awake, so I make him nap
这样我就能好好看电视
so I don't get gypped out of my TV time.
是这样  红毛  我亲自上门
Well, look, Red, I'm coming in there.
就是要亲眼看看乔治过得怎么样
With my own two eyes, I'm gonna get a good look at George.
这个东西
And this...
拦不住我
ain't stopping me.
好吧
Okay.
随你的便
Suit yourself.
他在里面吗
He back there?
走廊尽头的那扇门
Door at the end of the hallway.
你可能得摇醒他
You might have to shake him awake.
我今天早晨把他干翻了
I fucked his brains out this morning.
他可能累了
He may be tired.
八年前先生
Oh, Mr. Eight Years Ago?
乔治瞎了
George is blind,
所以你可能需要告诉他你是谁
so you'll probably have to tell him who you are.
乔治  你醒了吗
George, you awake?
乔治
George?
-乔治  -天啊
- George! - Jesus.
-乔治  -等等
- Hi, George. - Wait a minute.
-出什么事了  -什么事都没有
- What's going on? - Everything's all right.
-抱歉把你吵醒了  -你是谁
- I'm sorry to disturb you. - Uh... Who are you?
克利夫·布思
It's Cliff Booth.
过来问候一下  看你过得怎么样
Just stopped in to say hello and see how you're doing.
约翰·威尔克斯·布思
John Wilkes Booth?
不  克利夫·布思
No, Cliff Booth.
不认识
Who's that?
我以前在这拍过《赏金法》  乔治
I used to shoot Bounty Law here, George.
我以前是瑞克·道尔顿的替身
I was Rick Dalton's stunt double.
-谁  -瑞克·道尔顿
- Who? - Rick Dalton.
道尔顿兄弟吗
The Dalton Brothers?
不  瑞克·道尔顿
No, Rick Dalton.
不认识
Who's that?
他是《赏金法》的演员
He was the star of Bounty Law.
那你是谁
And who are you?
我是瑞克的替身
I was Rick's stunt double.
哪个瑞克
Rick who?
不重要了  乔治
It don't matter, George.
我们以前一起共事过  我只是想
We were colleagues from the past, and I just wanted
确认一下你一切都好
to make sure you're doing okay.
-我可不好  -出什么事了
- I'm not doing okay. - What's the matter?
我屁都看不见
Can't see shit.
你说这算不算"事"
Would you call that "The matter"?
这家伙狗屁都看不见
The man can't see shit, okay?
真遗憾  我听说了
I know. I'm sorry about that. I was told.
喳喳让我上床睡觉
Squeaky sent me to bed.
你说的是前面那个红头发小姑娘吗
Would that be the little redhead out front?
你是不是有病
What the fuck is the matter with you?
你先是吵醒我
First you wake me up,
现在又假装我没告诉你
and now you're pretending that I didn't tell you
我他妈是个瞎子
I was fucking blind!
我怎么知道一直跟我在一起的姑娘
How am I gonna know what the hell color the head
头发到底是什么颜色
of the girl is that's with me all the time?
好吧  乔治
Oh, fair enough, George.
- 不  天啊  -来  乔治
- No. Jesus Christ. - Come on, George. All right.
不是所有人都需要替身
Everyone don't need a stuntman.
我不知道你是谁
I don't know who you are...
但是你今天让我很感动
but you touched me today.
你来看望我
You came to visit me.
现在我要继续睡觉了
Now I got to go back to sleep.
我今晚要看《联邦调查局》
I got to watch F.B.I. tonight.
我要和喳喳一起看
I watch it with Squeaky.
我要是睡着了她会生气的
She gets all pissed off if I fall asleep.
她生气会怎样  乔治
What happens when she gets pissed off, George?
不会怎样
Nothing.
我只是不想让她失望
I just don't like to disappoint her.
所以你允许这些嬉皮士住在这里
So you gave all these hippies permission to be here?
你到底是谁
Just who the fuck are you?
我是克利夫·布思
I'm Cliff Booth.
我是一个替身演员
I'm a stuntman.
我们曾经是同事  乔治
We used to work together, George.
我只是想确认你没事
And I just want to make sure you're okay.
而且那些嬉皮士也没有占你便宜
And that all these hippies aren't taking advantage of you.
-喳喳  -对
- Squeaky? - Yeah.
她很爱我
She loves me.
看不惯忍着
So suck on that.
你多保重  乔治
You take care, George.
该死
Goddamn it.
你让我难堪了
You embarrassed me.
是的  对不起
Yeah, sorry about that.
你和乔治的叙旧怎么样
How'd your little talk with George go?
我们绑架他了吗
Are we kidnapping him?
我可没这么说
Not the word I'd use.
你已经跟他聊过了  这下你相信没事了吧
Now you've talked to him, you believe everything's all right?
并不是
Not exactly.
这是个错误  你应该离开
This was a mistake. You should leave.
早就知道了
Way ahead of you.
乔治没有瞎
George isn't blind!
瞎的人是你
You're the blind one!
你干的
You do that?
要知道  这不是我的车
You know, that's not my car.
是我老板的
That's my boss's car.
要是我老板的车出了什么问题
And if something were to happen to my boss's car,
我会有麻烦的
well, I'd get in trouble.
算你走运  他有一个备用胎
Lucky for you, he has got a spare.
给我修好
Fix it.
去你的
Fuck you.
-别欺负他  -他那么娇弱
- Leave him alone! - He's a flower!
别打了
He's a flower, man.
他什么都不懂
He's just a flower. He doesn't know better.
女士们
Ladies.
再靠近一步我就把他的牙都打出来
Come one step closer and I will knock his teeth out.
修好
Fix it.
能给我一块布  我先擦擦脸吗
Can I at least get a rag to wipe my face first?
不行
Nope.
先修轮胎
Tire first.
-圣丹丝  -在
- Sundance. - Yeah.
骑马去找泰克斯  让他赶紧下来
Get on a horse, go get Tex and get his ass down here.
好的
Okay.
我爱你
I love you.
泰克斯  泰克斯
Tex! Tex!
那个夏威夷男的把克莱姆的脸都打飞了
That Hawaiian guy's back at the ranch kicking Clem's face in.
这个混蛋
Ah, son of a...
我来接替泰克斯
I'll take over for Tex.
这边请
Right this way.
驾  驾
Hyah! Hyah!
克莱姆  你没事吧
Clem, you all right?
怎么样
How do?
真是糟糕  我差点疯了
What a day. Shit, I almost lost my shit.
你
You, uh...
你要不要进来一起看我演的《联邦调查局》
You want to come in and watch my F.B.I.?
我也这么想的  我买了一提酒放在后面
Why, I just figured we would. I got a six-pack in the back.
打算订披萨来着
Thought we'd order a pizza.
好吧
All right.
好的
联调局的使命是保护无辜民众
揪出美国政府的敌人
离彭德尔顿还有18英里  威拉德
Eighteen miles to Pendleton, Willard.
走运的话  能赶在我孩子睡觉前
Any kind of luck, we'll be unloaded
卸完货赶回埃尔托罗
and back at El Toro before my kids go to bed.
我今天买了一根酸泡香烟[含迷幻药]
Hey, bought me an acid-dipped cigarette today.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
你想买一根被酸泡过的香烟吗
You want to buy a cigarette dipped in acid?
是的
Yeah.
我要嗨的话也是在这嗨
If I'm gonna trip, I want to trip here, man.
在树林里漫步  而不是在我家
Walk in the woods. Not in my home.
我把它藏这了
Just gonna stash it here.
-别不小心抽错了  -好的
- Don't smoke it by mistake. - Yeah.
你要是想抽的话就抽  给我留点就行
You want to smoke some, smoke some. Just save me some.
不  我不需要嗑药嗨
Nah, I don't need to trip out on no acid.
我有酒就够了
My booze don't need no buddy.
我出场了  我出场了
Here I come. Here I come.
怎么了  下士
What's the trouble, corporal?
有辆卡车跟着我们  长官
There's a truck tailing us, sir.
可能是个着急赶路的农民
It might be a farmer in a hurry to get someplace.
好吧
Oh, fine.
那你就快点开
Well, take it as fast as you can.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
那是太平洋海岸公路吗
That PCH?
是的  对  马布里
Yeah, yeah. Malibu.
普埃科峡谷之类的  我也不知道
Puerco Canyon or some shit. I don't know.
麻烦来了
Here comes trouble.
天啊  爆头
Oh, man. Right in the face.
这一跳挺利索
That was a smooth leap.
谢谢
Thank you.
死尸二号
Dead number two.
这镜头我喜欢
I like that shot.
那个家伙就是个变态
That guy's a fucking prick.
那个是波比·霍根  好人
Um, that's Bobby Hogan. Good guy.
好吧  我的联调局高光时刻来了
All right, get ready for my big F.B.I. moment.
-他们都死了  -很好
- They're all dead, babe. - Good.
迈克尔·墨脱
偷盗政府财产
"迈克尔·墨脱"
"Michael Murtaugh."
-《联邦调查局》  -迈克尔·墨脱
- The F.B.I. - Michael Murtaugh.
你好啊  塞尔吉奥
Buongiorno, Sergio.
快看第七频道
Turn on Channel 7.
ABC台的
ABC.
《联邦调查局》
F.B.I.
我找到你的《内布拉斯加的吉姆》合适人选了
I'm watching your Nebraska Jim as we speak.
菲利普·阿尔伯特  威廉·雷诺兹
...Philip Abbott, William Reynolds.
客串的还有詹姆斯·法兰蒂诺
With guest stars James Farentino,
瑞克·道尔顿
Rick Dalton...
喜欢我嚼口香糖吗
Like the chewing gum?
-诺尔曼·费尔  -特别喜欢
- Norman Fell. - Strong.
今晚剧集
Tonight's episode:
《无声的街道》
"All the Streets Are Silent."
除了瑞克·道尔顿中枪的时候
Except when Rick Dalton's got a fucking shotgun,
-跟你说  -你说得对
- I'll tell you that. - You're goddamn right.
六个月之后
1969年8月8日  星期五
看着真好喝
Well, that looks delicious.
-谢谢  -慢用  先生
- Thank you. - Enjoy, sir.
在穆索和弗兰克餐厅吃过午饭之后
After that Musso & Frank's lunch meeting,
马文确实给了瑞克意大利拍电影的工作机会
Marvin did provide Rick job opportunities in the Italian film industry.
瑞克·道尔顿  我是马文·施瓦兹  稍等
Rick Dalton, Marvin Schwarz here. Hold on.
轩尼诗XO加冰
Hennessy X.O on the rocks.
好的  施瓦兹先生
Yes, Mr. Schwarz.
两个名
Two words.
《内布拉斯加的吉姆》  塞尔吉奥·科尔布奇
Nebraska Jim, Sergio Corbucci.
内布拉斯加什么
N-Nebraska what?
塞尔吉奥谁
Sergio who?
塞尔吉奥·科尔布奇
Sergio Corbucci.
那是谁
A-and who's that?
世界第二厉害的
The second-best director
意大利西部片导演
of Spaghetti Westerns in the whole wide world.
他在拍一部新的西部片  叫《内布拉斯加的吉姆》
He's doing a new Western. It's called Nebraska Jim.
正因为我  他考虑用你
And because of me, he's considering you.
《内布拉斯加的吉姆》
瑞克参演了《内布拉斯加的吉姆》
Well, Rick got Nebraska Jim.
他演的内布拉斯加的吉姆确实引人入胜
And Rick made a rather compelling Nebraska Jim,
和塞尔吉奥·科尔布奇拍的
existing quite nicely within
一系列非典型英雄很相符
Sergio Corbucci's rogues gallery of antiheroes.
在罗马  瑞克非常喜欢狗仔队
In Rome, Rick loved the paparazzi
和他们给他制造的话题
and the fuss they made over him
以及他的联合主演达芙娜·本科博
and his Nebraska Jim costar Daphna Ben-Cobo.
-好了  狗仔们  -好的  慢点
- All right there, paparazzos. - All right. Take it easy.
他非常喜欢那里的食物
He loved the food so much that during his stay,
那段时间他胖了13斤
Rick gained almost 15 pounds.
但是他不喜欢意大利人拍电影的方式
But he didn't love the Italians' way of making movies.
电影片段
《内布拉斯加的吉姆》片场
事实上  他认为这种靠后期配音
In fact, he thought the post-synced,
"每个演员各说各话"的
"Every actor speaks their own language,"
这种巴别塔式的欧洲电影拍摄风格非常荒谬
Tower of Babel shooting style of European movies was ridiculous.
在罗马期间  马文给瑞克
While in Rome, Marvin plugged Rick
排了其他三部意大利电影
into three other Italian productions.
他的第二部西部片是
His second Western was
《外国佬说  快点杀了我  林格》
Kill Me Quick, Ringo, Said the Gringo,
还有约瑟夫·科腾主演
also starring Joseph Cotten
卡尔文·杰克逊·佩吉特导演
and directed by Calvin Jackson Padget,
《外国佬说  快点杀了我  林格》
是希奥尔希奥·费罗尼导演的假名
pseudonym for Giorgio Ferroni.
《红血红肤》
他的第三部片子是意大利和西班牙合拍的
His third was an Italian/Spanish coproduction
与泰利·萨瓦拉斯共同主演的
that paired him with Telly Savalas,
《红血红肤》
titled Red Blood, Red Skin,
华金·罗密欧·马尚导演
directed by Joaquin Romero Marchent
根据弗洛伊德·雷伊·威尔逊的小说
and based on the Floyd Raye Wilson novel,
《唯一的好印度人》改编的
The Only Good Indian Is a Dead Indian.
第四部  是意大利谍战片
And his fourth, a Spaghetti secret agent,
007式的《最佳行动》
James Bond rip-off-type flick called Operazione Dyn-O-Mite!,
《最佳行动》
安东尼奥·马格瑞特导演的
directed by Antonio Margheriti.
克利夫
最终  瑞克在意大利的这六个月赚得盆满钵满
Ultimately making Rick's six-month italian sojourn fairly profitable,
尽管他拉风的罗马公寓
although his swank Roman apartment
花掉了他收入的一大部分
ate up a big chunk of his earnings.
瑞克乘坐泛美航空回到好莱坞的时候
So as Rick returns to Hollywood via Pan Am,
他名下有四部新作品
he has four new movies under his belt,
兜里有一点钱
some money in his pocket,
还有他全新的意大利老婆
and his brand-spanking-new Italian wife,
斯嘉丽·弗兰切斯卡·卡布奇
Starlet Francesca Cappucci.
瑞克在空中飞驰而过
Hurtling through the air
奔向新生活和未知的未来
towards a new life and uncertain future,
不确定前方有什么等着他
Rick was really not sure about what lay ahead for him.
在很后面的经济舱
Way back in coach,
克利夫·布思喝着无限续杯的血腥玛丽
working on his bottomless Bloody Mary,
也在返回洛杉矶的途中
Cliff Booth returned to Los Angeles as well.
他全程陪着瑞克
He kept Rick company
在意大利整整待了六个月
during his entire six-month stay in Italy.
当地
西班牙  阿尔梅里亚
拍摄《红血红肤》时
然而  当二位回到家后
However, as the two men return home,
他们达成了一个共识
they've come to an understanding.
是这样的...
Well, here it goes now.
有了...
With the, uh...
有了新老婆  我...
With the new wife, I, uh...
我请不起你了  克利夫  知道吗
I just I can't afford you anymore, Cliff. You know?
我自己的房子都快要供不起了
I can barely afford my own house anymore.
所以我的计划是把房子卖了
So I think the plan is to sell the house
在托卢卡湖买一套公寓  把剩下的钱存起来
and buy-buy a condo in-in-in Toluca Lake, bank the money.
靠这个支撑  这之类的
You know, live off it. That type of thing.
希望接下来的试播季我能接到戏
Hopefully, I score come next pilot season.
好计划
That's a good plan.
是啊
Yeah.
到时候就知道我到底能不能闯出事业了
You know, by then, I'll know if I have a career or not,
看看我是会像艾迪·奥布莱恩说的那样
if I'm a solid Los Angeles citizen
变成个实打实的洛杉矶人
like Eddie O'Brien says,
还是会离回密苏里更近一步
or if I'm one step closer to going back to Missouri.
所以等这整趟欧洲之旅结束后
So when this whole European journey is over,
我觉得我们...
I think we've, uh...
已经走到尽头了  克利夫
We've reached the end of the trail, Cliff.
这最后四部意大利片子
So these last four Italian flicks,
是克利夫和瑞克共事九年之后
after nine years together,
最后的合作了
would be Rick and Cliff's final rodeo.
克利夫不知道自己之后要干些什么
Cliff doesn't have a clue what he's gonna do.
两人唯一确定的就是
The only thing the two men know of for sure:
今晚  瑞克和克利夫要一起不醉不归
Tonight, Rick and Cliff will have a good old-fashioned drunk.
两人都知道
Both men know,
飞机降落埃尔塞贡多市的那一刻
once the plane touches down in El Segundo,
对两人而言  就是一个时代的结束了
it'll be the end of an era for both of them.
当你和一位朋友一起走到尽头
And when you come to the end of the line with a buddy
而这位朋友于你而言远超兄弟之情
who is more than a brother and a little less than a wife,
一起喝个烂醉真的是道别的唯一方式
getting blind drunk together is really the only way to say farewell.
到了  亲爱的
Here it is, honey.
-喜欢吗  -爱死了
- You like it? - I love it.
你想摆哪里
Where do you want it?
时间
12:30
喂
Hello?
我是乔安娜  带着宝宝
Hey, it's Joanna and the baby.
你好呀  快请进
Hi! Come on up.
你好呀
Hi!
亲爱的  你还好吗
Oh, honey. How are you?
-天呀  你快生了吧  -是啊
- Oh, my gosh, you're about to pop! - I know!
-这间是婴儿房  -天呀  莎伦
- And this is the nursery. - Oh, my God, Sharon.
-太完美了  -你喜欢吗
- It's perfect. - Do you love it?
-小鞋子  -是呀
- Little shoes! - I know.
我快撑死了
I'm about to burst.
-你会是一个很棒的母亲  -谢谢
- I think you're gonna be a wonderful mother. - Thank you.
时间
3:00
5:00
-谢了  吉莉安  -拜  拜  布兰迪
- Thanks, Gillian. - Bye! Bye, Brandy!
罗曼在伦敦准备他的下一部电影时
Sharon had two friends move into the Cielo Drive residence
莎伦让两个朋友搬进了天堂道的住所
while Roman was in London preparing his next movie:
沃伊特克·弗里科夫斯基
Voytek Frykowski,
罗曼的波兰老朋友
an old friend of Roman's from Poland,
以及他的女友  社工阿比盖尔·福尔杰
and his girlfriend, social worker Abigail Folger,
庞大的福尔杰咖啡帝国的继承人
heiress to the vast Folger coffee empire.
那天晚上  莎伦  她的两位客人
That night, Sharon, her two houseguests
时间
7:00
当然了  还有杰...
and, naturally, Jay...
都去了西好莱坞的知名墨西哥餐厅
all went to the West Hollywood mexican restaurant landmark
位于比弗利的土狼餐厅  吃晚餐
El Coyote, on Beverly, for dinner.
那个色情片影院在干什么
What's going on at the dirty movie place?
在举办首映式
Oh, they're having a premiere.
色情片还有首映式吗
Dirty movies have premieres?
是啊  特好玩
Yeah. They're fun.
-这家餐厅总是这么多人  -是啊
- This place is always so busy. - I know.
太多人了
It's crazy in here.
这里是你们的位置
And right here for you.
-先生们请坐  -谢了
- Gentlemen. - Oh. Thanks.
8:30左右的时候  瑞克和克利夫
While closer to 8:30, Rick and Cliff
时间
8:32
去了圣费尔南多谷的知名墨西哥餐厅
went to the Valley Mexican restaurant landmark
位于文图拉的卡萨维加
Casa Vega on Ventura.
你好  欢迎
Hello. Welcome.
不客气  先生
You're welcome, sir.
啧啧啧  这不是铁胆威龙本人嘛
Well, well, well, if it ain't the cobra himself.
-你好呀  道格  近来如何  -你好呀
- Hey, Doug. What's happening? - How you doing?
-很高兴见到你  -你老婆怎么样
- It's good to see you. - How's the wife?
开玩笑的  开玩笑的
I'm just kidding. I'm just kidding.
布兰迪留在了瑞克家里
Brandy stayed behind at Rick's house,
守护着在床上熟睡的美丽的意大利女人
guarding the beautiful Italian woman asleep in her bed
等着克利夫和瑞克回家...
and waiting for Cliff and Rick to come home...
而倒时差的弗兰切斯卡正在睡梦中
while jet-lagged Francesca slept.
但你只有在给他理发的日子
But you just get paid for the day
-才有工资领吧  对吗  -不不不
- that you cut his hair, right? - No, no, no.
1000美元是我的日收入
I get paid $1000 a day.
在我到的那天能拿1000美元  在我...
I get paid $1000 the day I arrive. I get paid $1000...
在野狼餐厅
At El Coyote,
大家都在饮用玛格丽塔  欢度快乐时光
margaritas and good times were had by all,
除了莎伦
except Sharon.
莎伦正在经历由妊娠引起的情绪低落
Sharon was experiencing a touch of pregnancy-induced melancholy.
除此之外
Not only that,
之后也有报道称那晚是当年最热的一晚
it was later reported that it was the hottest night of the year,
这让她以各种最糟糕的方式体会了怀孕
and it made her feel especially pregnant in all the worst ways.
我不想再去派对狂欢了  我累了
I don't want to party anymore. I am tired.
因为他能把片子拍出来
Because he got it done.
不  不止...不止是因为他能拍出来
No, it's not... It's not because he just got it done.
他和其他导演的时间是一样多的
He had just as much time as all the rest of the goddamn directors.
他如何利用时间...这才是重点
What he did with that time... That's what counted.
在卡萨维加  瑞克和克利夫喝高了
At Casa Vega, Rick and Cliff drank so much that,
等他们离开的时候  他们没开那辆凯迪拉克
when they left, they left the Cadillac there
而是打车回家的
and took a cab home.
最伟大的动作片导演
The greatest action director,
有史以来最被低估的
underrated guy of all time.
十点左右  莎伦和她的朋友们
Around 10, Sharon and her friends
时间
10:16
离开了野狼餐厅  回到了她的家中
left El Coyote and arrived back at her house.
你喝了...大概有19杯玛格丽塔吧
You've had, like, 19 margaritas.
他们四个人多玩了一会儿
The four of them hung out a little longer,
阿比盖尔还为他们弹了钢琴...
with Abigail even playing the piano for them...
*别惹我生气  别对我撒谎*
*Don't get me mad. Don't tell no lie.*
*别让我伤心  别对我视而不见*
*Don't make me sad. Don't pass me by.*
*宝贝  你是否抓住了一切*
*Baby, are you holding?*
*抓住了一切  却放开了我*
*Holding anything but me?*
*因为我坦率直白  如果你明白的话*
*'Cause I'm a real straight shooter, if you know what I mean.*
*你能带来爱情  你能伴我身侧*
*You can bring me love. You can hang around.*
*你能让我开心快乐  不要让我伤心低落*
*You can bring me up. Don't you bring me down.*
然后她才回了房
until she returned to her room,
抽了一根大麻烟卷  读了会儿书
smoked a joint and read a book.
那时是11点左右
That was around 11.
时间
11:04
我也爱你  查尔斯
I love you too, Charles.
接下来是我知道你们一直在等的东西
And now it's time for what I know you've all been waiting for.
请来点音乐
A little fanfare please!
《电视指南》
电视裸露之时
在差不多同一时刻
At more or less the same time,
沃伊特克躺在沙发上看着美国电视节目
Voytek laid on the couch watching American television
思考着它比波兰电视节目高明多少
and thought about how much better it was than Polish television,
与此同时抽了一大根大麻烟卷
as he smoked a big joint.
11:10左右的时候
Somewhere around 11:10,
时间
11:10
莎伦换上了舒适的家居服
Sharon changed into her comfy house attire.
感觉好点了吗
Feel better?
感觉好太多了
That is drastically better.
当黄色出租车
It was after 11:45 by the time
时间
11:46
把瑞克和克利夫放到家门口时
the yellow cab dropped Rick and Cliff
已经过了11:45了
in front of the house.
谢谢  就是这里
Thank you. Right here.
好了  谢了 朋友
All right. Grazie, amigo.
-多少钱  -3美元
- How much do I owe you? - Three dollars.
布兰迪很高兴他们回来了
Brandy was glad to see them return.
-谢了  兄弟  -谢谢
- Thank you, brother. - Thanks.
再来几杯玛格丽塔
More margaritas.
午夜时分
Around midnight,
时间
12:03
一个彻底醉了的瑞克·道尔顿
a completely drunk Rick Dalton
开始制作玛格丽塔冰沙
started making a blender of frozen margaritas.
好了
All right.
-我们去散步  -与此同时
- We're walking. - At the same time,
克利夫正在给兴奋的布兰迪套上狗绳
Cliff was attaching a leash to an excited Brandy's dog collar.
我知道
I know.
我还记得你
I remember you.
酸泡烟卷
A cigarette dipped in acid.
-有什么用  -抽它  能让你嗨
- What's that do? - You smoke it. It gets you high.
-多少钱  -五十美分
- How much? - Fifty cents.
五十美分
Fifty cents.
嬉皮妞  五十美分
Hippie girl, 50 cents.
就选今晚了吗
Tonight the night?
为什么不呢
Why not?
走咯
And away we go.
我们的波兰朋友  说那天是当年最热的一天
Our Polish friend said it was the hottest day of the year.
虽然这话是他说的
Despite the fact that he said it,
但还真可能是真的
actually, it might be true.
该死的
Goddamn.
这他妈是私人道路
Fucking private road.
死贵的房产税你帮我交啊
Damn property taxes up the butt.
该死的
Goddamn.
一群该死的嬉皮士
Bunch of goddamn fucking hippies.
搞什么鬼
What the fuck?
喂  你们
Hey, you!
王八蛋  我就是说你们呢
Yeah, asshole, I'm talking to you!
你们他妈是在干什么
What the hell do you think you're doing
大半夜的开辆吵死人的破车来这里
bringing that noisy hunk of shit around here at midnight?
这条是私人道路  明白吗
This is a private road, all right?
你们是什么人  来找谁的
Who are you? And who are you here to see?
不找谁  先生  我们只是迷路了
Nobody, sir. We just got lost and a little turned around.
放狗屁
Ah, horseshit.
你们这群死嬉皮士上来这里
You fucking hippies came up here
是想在黑漆漆的小路上抽大麻的吧
to smoke dope on a dark road, huh?
下次你想这么干  把你那破排气管修修
Next time you want to try that, fix your fucking muffler.
我们很抱歉打扰到你了
Look, we're really sorry we disturbed you.
大哥  你们不属于这里
Look, chief, you don't belong here.
赶紧开着这辆王八蛋
Now, take this mechanical asshole
从我的街道上滚蛋
and get it off my fucking street!
丹尼斯·霍珀  快把这辆破玩意开走
Dennis Hopper! Move this fucking piece of shit!
《逍遥骑士》导演兼主演
好的  给我点时间调个头
All right. Just give me a moment to turn it around.
直接倒出去  蠢货
Drive it backwards, numbnuts,
赶紧开走  立刻马上
but fucking drive it, and drive it now!
好的  好的  别吼了
Okay. Okay. Stop yelling.
别急  我们这就走
Hold your horses. We're leaving.
你他妈看什么呢  你个红发小王八蛋
The hell are you looking at, you little ginger-haired fucker?
你们再到这边来  我他妈就报警了
Hey, you come around here again, I'm gonna call the fucking cops!
臭嬉皮士
Dirty fucking hippies.
坐在他那豪华的家中
There in his fancy fucking house,
觉得自己无所不能
thinking he's handled it.
但他看见我们了  他还醒着  他很警觉
But he's seen us. He's awake. He's alert.
他们都还醒着  他们在他妈的听唱片呢
They're all awake. They're listening to fucking records.
所有人都还他妈的醒着
Everybody's fucking awake!
听好了
Look!
-查理是怎么说的  -他说
- What did Charlie say? - He said:
"去泰瑞的老房子  杀了里面所有人"
"Go to Terry's old house and kill everybody in there."
你们自己也听见了  他说"搞得邪气一点"
And you heard him yourself. He said, "Make it witchy."
要么他真这么说过
Now, he either said that,
要么我是个骗子
or I'm a liar.
你们有人觉得我是个骗子吗
Now, are any one of you calling me a liar?
你呢
How about you?
你觉得我是骗子吗
Are you calling me a liar?
不  当然不是
No, of course not.
很好
Good.
等等
Hold it.
-刚刚那是瑞克·道尔顿吗  -谁
- Was that Rick Dalton? - Who?
《赏金法》里的那人
The guy from Bounty Law.
-演谁  杰克·卡希尔吗  -对啊
- Who, Jake Cahill? - Yeah.
刚刚那个穿着睡袍的人是杰克·卡希尔
That guy in the robe was Jake Cahill.
等等
Wait a minute.
刚刚吼我的是他妈杰克·卡希尔
That was fucking Jake Cahill that just yelled at me?
刚刚那人老一些  但我觉得是的
He was older, but, yeah, I think so.
这个叫瑞克的是谁
So who's this Rick guy?
老天啊  莎蒂  动动脑子
Jesus Christ, Sadie, get it together.
瑞克·道尔顿在五十年代一部名叫《赏金法》的
Rick Dalton played Jake Cahill on a cowboy show
牛仔电影里演了杰克·卡希尔
in the '50s called Bounty Law.
操你妈  凯蒂
Fuck you, Katie.
抱歉我不了解五十年代
Sorry I don't know the name
电视上每个法西斯主义者的名字
of every fascist on TV in the '50s.
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe
那个穿着睡袍的王八蛋居然是杰克·卡希尔
that asshole in the robe was Jake Cahill.
我小时候有个《赏金法》的午餐盒
When I was a kid, I had a Bounty Law lunch box.
那是我所有的午餐盒中最喜欢的一个
That was my favorite of all my lunch boxes.
听听这个
Dig this!
我们抽嗨了的时候
When we've been having our trip sessions,
我一直在脑子里思索一个点子
I've been expanding on this one idea in my head.
好了  听好了
All right, dig it.
我们是看着电视长大的  你们懂我意思吧
We all grew up watching TV, you know what I mean?
如果你是看着电视长大的
And if you grew up watching TV,
那就意味着你是看着谋杀长大的
that means you grew up watching murder.
电视里播的每一部电视剧
Every show on TV
情景喜剧
只要不是《我爱露茜》  就都是讲谋杀的
that wasn't I Love Lucy was about murder.
所以我的想法是...
So my idea is...
我们去杀教我们杀人的人
we kill the people who taught us to kill.
我们他妈的在哪呢
I mean, where the fuck are we, man?
在该死的好莱坞啊
We are in fucking Hollywood, man.
整整一代人都是看着这里的人杀人长大的
The people an entire generation grew up watching kill people live here.
而这些杀人凶手却住在这里吃香喝辣
And they live in pig-shit fucking luxury.
去他们的吧
I say fuck them.
我们应该割掉他们的老二让他们吃下去
I say we cut their cocks off and make them eat it.
真是个好主意  莎蒂
That's a great idea, Sadie.
你们两个准备好杀猪猡了吗
You two ready to kill some piggies?
等一下  该死
Wait a minute. Oh, shit.
对不起  我把刀忘在车里了
Sorry, I forgot my knife in the car.
我可以去...我能回去拿吗
Can I go...? Can I go back and get it?
-去吧  -好
- Yeah, sure. - Okay.
-快去  等一下  -怎么了
- Go on. Wait a minute. - What?
车锁上了  给你钥匙
I locked the car. You'll need keys to get in.
对  谢谢
Right. Thank you.
-我去去就回  -好
- Okay. I'll be right back. - Okay.
-快点  -好  马上
- Just hurry up. - Yeah, just a little minute.
这个臭婊子
Oh, that fucking bitch!
嘘  小点声
Shh! Calm down.
那边就有一栋房子
There's a fucking house right there.
现在怎么办
What do we do now?
该怎么办就怎么办
We do what we came to do.
干完之后  各自搭车回家
And when we're done, we split up and hitch home.
还有问题吗
Any more questions?
好了猪猡杀手们  去杀猪吧
Okay, pig killers, let's kill some piggies.
好
All right.
有人饿了啊
Oh, someone's hungry.
好了
All right.
开饭了
It's feeding time.
布兰迪  上沙发
Brandy, couch.
不许动...
And don't you mo...
天啊
Oh, man.
火车已经离开站台了
The train has left the station.
开什么灯啊
Bad idea.
恶犬的美食
你绕过去  看看有没有后门
You go around there, see if there's a back entrance.
明白了吗  去吧
All right? Go.
现在这种情况  我已经尽力了
I am doing the best I can under the circumstances.
我今晚不想跟你说这个
Now, I do not want to get into it tonight.
需要帮忙吗
Can I help you?
该死
Shit.
这里还有多少人
How many other people are here?
就一个在里面睡觉的
Oh, just the one sleeping in the back there.
去叫醒他  把他带到客厅来
Go get him and bring him into the living room.
他要是不来怎么办
What if he says no?
不来不行
Don't take no for an answer.
你手里可有刀  去把他带来
You're the one with the knife. Get him in here!
你是真的吧
You are real, right?
我像甜甜圈一样真实  混蛋
I'm as real as a doughnut, motherfucker.
什么情况
What the fuck?
去客厅
Go to the living room.
这是怎么回事
What is going on, huh?
-快走  -好  好
- Go! - Okay. Si, si.
这他妈是谁
Who the fuck's that?
我不知道
I don't know.
弗兰切斯卡
Francesca.
什么...
What...?
我认识你
Oh, I know you.
你们三个我都认识
I know all three of you.
没错  斯潘牧场
Yeah. Spahn Ranch.
斯潘牧场
Spahn Ranch. Yeah. Hoo!
我不知道你叫什么  但是我记得你的头发
I don't know your name, but I remember that hair.
还有你  我记得你那苍白的小脸
And you, I remember your white little face.
还有你骑着马
And you were on a horsie.
没错
Yeah.
你是...
You are...?
我是魔鬼
I'm the devil,
我来做魔鬼的事
and I'm here to do the devil's business.
不是  你的名字比这蠢多了
Nah, it was dumber than that.
好像是...雷克斯
Something like... Rex.
-天啊  打死他  泰克斯  -泰克斯
- God, shoot him, Tex! - Tex.
操
Fuck!
他妈的
Son of a bitch!
喂  你
Hey, you.
竟敢闯进我家来  混蛋
How dare you come into my house, motherfucker!
哎呀呀
Wow, man.
什么鬼
What the fuck?
我的天啊
Jesus Christ.
天啊
Holy shit.
弗兰切斯卡  弗兰切斯卡  宝贝
Francesca! Francesca, honey!
天堂道  10000街区
10,000 block, Cielo Drive.
你大约是什么时间遭遇这名入侵者的
Around what time was it when you confronted the intruder?
大概是午夜
It was about midnight.
-午夜  -是的
- Around midnight? - Yeah.
你怎么知道是午夜
How do you know it was midnight?
我当时  我当时在厨房
Well, I was, uh... I was in the kitchen.
在调玛格丽塔  然后...
You know, I was making margaritas, and, uh...
我听到了很吵的汽车声
I heard the sound of a noisy muffler.
我抬头看了下钟
I looked up at the clock.
上面的时间就是午夜
It said... The kitchen clock said midnight.
正好十二点吗
Twelve o'clock exactly?
也可能是十二点零五
I mean, it could have been 12:05.
-差不多那个时候  -然后你就再没看到他们
- Something like that. - And you didn't see them again
直到那个女人在泳池里袭击你
until the woman attacked you in the pool.
是的
No, no.
所以这些行凶者做了什么
So, what did these perpetrators do?
行凶者  他们就是一群傻逼嬉皮士
Perpetrators? They were hippie assholes.
两个嬉皮士从前门闯进来
Two of them burst through the front door there,
其中那个男的说他是魔鬼
and the guy hippie said he was the devil.
他还说  "我来做...
And he said, "I'm here to...
什么魔鬼的事"
do some devil shit."
不是他的原话  但是...
Or... That's not verbatim, but...
-"魔鬼的事"  -对  "魔鬼的事"
- "Some devil shit"? - Yeah, "Devil shit."
我们走
And away we go.
等等  等等
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
你去哪家医院  克利夫
What hospital you going to, Cliff?
我们那里见好吗
I'll meet you there, huh?
别来医院找我
You don't want to meet me in no hospital.
去照顾你太太吧
Why don't you go take care of your lady.
她刚吃了五片安眠药
She just took five fucking sleeping pills.
能一直睡到十月的哥伦布日
She'll be asleep till Columbus Day.
这些家伙可能还得再来一次
These guys will probably have to come out here again
-把她弄醒  -我不会死的
- just to wake her ass up. - Hey, I'm not gonna die.
可能会瘸  但不会死的
I may get a limp, but I ain't gonna die.
-我的时间还没到  -好吧
- It's not my time yet, man. - All right.
所以不需要来医院看我
So no use waiting in some waiting room.
你现在应该脱光光钻进你老婆的被窝
Why don't you go lie naked with that fine creature.
明天再来看我吧
Come visit me tomorrow.
带甜甜圈来
Bring bagels.
你要是想为我做点什么  就照顾好布兰迪
You want to do something for me, check on Brandy.
她可能有点受惊
She may be a little shook up after that.
-可能会想跟你一起睡  -开玩笑
- She may want to sleep with you. - Are you kidding me?
她正跟弗兰切斯卡一起睡呢
She's sleeping with Francesca right now.
你可能再也领不回她了
You might never get her back. Ha, ha.
-我们得走了  -好的  克利夫
- We got to go. - All right, then, Cliff.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow, then.
你是个好朋友  克利夫
You're a good friend, Cliff.
我尽力
I try.
你好
Hello?
我是杰·赛百灵
I'm Jay Sebring.
波兰斯基家的朋友
I'm a friend of the Polanskis.
你是瑞克·道尔顿吧
You're Rick Dalton, right?
是的  我是瑞克·道尔顿
Yeah. Yeah. I'm Rick Dalton.
-住在隔壁  -我知道
- Live next door. - Oh, I know.
我还取笑莎伦说她就住在杰克·卡希尔的隔壁
I tease Sharon that she lives next door to Jake Cahill.
如果她想悬赏捉拿罗曼
If she ever wants to put a bounty on Roman,
只要走去隔壁就可以了
she just has to go next door, right?
说的对啊
No shit.
刚刚是发生什么事了
What the fuck happened?
那些该死的嬉皮士怪胎
Oh, th-these fucking hippie weirdos,
他们闯进了我家
they-they-they broke into my house.
什么意思  他们想抢劫你吗
What do you mean, like, trying to rob you?
我们不知道他们到底想干什么
We don't know what the fuck they wanted.
是要抢我吗  我不确定
Were they robbing me? I don't know.
还是嗑药磕嗨了乱来
Were they freaking out on some bummer trip?
谁知道呢  但他们想杀了我太太和我兄弟
Who knows? But they tried to kill my wife and my buddy.
-天啊  你说真的  -当然了
- Jesus Christ. Are you serious? - Yeah, I'm fucking serious.
我兄弟和他的狗干掉了其中两个  然后...
Now, my buddy and his dog killed two of them, and then...
妈的  我烧死了最后一个
Well, shit. I-I torched the last one.
-烧死  -是的
- "Torched"? - Yeah.
我把她烧成了焦炭
I burnt her ass to a crisp.
-你怎么做到的  -说出来你可能不信
- How'd you do that? - Well, believe it or not, I...
我的工具房里有一把喷火器
I got a flamethrower in my toolshed.
《麦克拉斯基的十四拳》里那把
Oh, from The Fourteen Fists of McCluskey.
没错
Yeah!
就是那把
That's... That's the one.
而且它还能用  感谢上帝
Yeah, it still works too. Thank God.
大家都还好吧
Is everybody okay?
那些该死的嬉皮士可不怎么好
Well, the fucking hippies aren't,
这是肯定的
that's for goddamn sure.
但我很好
Yeah. But I'm fine.
我老婆也没事
You know, my wife's fine.
只是有点受惊而已
We're just a little shook up, is all.
-天啊  太可怕了  -是啊
- Oh, my God, that's terrifying. - Yeah.
杰  亲爱的  外面没事吧
Jay, honey, is everything all right?
现在没事了  亲爱的
Everything's okay now, honey.
但有几个嬉皮士闯进了隔壁邻居家
But some hippies broke into the house next door.
天啊
Oh, my God.
太可怕了
Oh, that's terrifying.
大家都没事吧
Is everybody okay?
我现在正和你的邻居说这事呢
I'm talking to your next-door neighbor about it right now.
瑞克·道尔顿
Rick Dalton?
对  是我
Yeah, that's me.
你好啊  邻居
Well, hello, neighbor.
你们都没事吧
Is everybody okay?
是的  莎伦  大家都没事
Yes, Sharon, everybody's fine.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
我很好  谢谢你的关心
Well, yes, I am. Thank you for asking that.
瑞克  你愿意到我家来
Rick, would you like to come up to the house
喝一杯  见见我其他的朋友吗
for a drink and meet my other friends?
当然  谢谢你
Yeah, sure. Thank you.
太好了  我开门让你进来
Oh, hooray! Great. I'll buzz you up.
进来吧
Come on.
很高兴见到你
Hey, nice to meet you, huh?
-杰·赛百灵  -很荣幸
- Jay Sebring. - Hey, pleasure.
很荣幸  杰
Pleasure, Jay.
我很荣幸
Pleasure's all mine.
听起来这一晚可够你受的
Sounds like you had a hell of a night.
-你好啊  瑞克  -莎伦  你好
- Hi, Rick. - Sharon, hi.
真高兴终于见到你了
It's so nice to finally meet you.
你还好吗
How are you?
这位是瑞克·道尔顿  很棒的演员
Rick Dalton. He's a wonderful actor.
快进来吧
Well, come on inside.
-喝点什么吗  -好啊
- Do you want a drink? - Yeah.
好莱坞往事
大家好  我是瑞克·道尔顿
Hi. This is Rick Dalton,
赏金猎人杰克·卡希尔
better known as bounty hunter Jake Cahill,
我在这里为红苹果香烟代言
speaking on behalf of Red Apple cigarettes.
我自己就抽红苹果香烟  抽了好多年
Now, I smoke Red Apples. Been smoking them for years.
因为红苹果烟草公司
But since the Red Apple tobacco company's
创始于1862年
been around since 1862,
所以你们会看到杰克·卡希尔也抽红苹果
you'll see Jake Cahill smoke Red Apple too.
在杰克那个年代  红苹果是袋装的烟草
Now, back in Jake's day, Red Apple came in a pouch,
他得自己卷烟才行
and he had to roll his own.
但是现在  红苹果在出厂时就卷好了
But today, Red Apple comes factory-rolled.
用最好的烟草获得最好的体验
For the best drag with the best tobacco flavor,
比其他任何未经过滤的香烟
with less burn on your throat
都更能减少喉咙的灼烧感
than any other non-filtered cigarette.
这才是香烟的味道
Now, that's the way a cigarette should taste.
更好抽  更好的烟味
Better drag, more flavor,
更不伤喉咙
less throat burn.
这就是红苹果的风格
That's the Red Apple way.
快去寻找杰克·卡希尔的等身立牌吧
So look for this life-size standee of me, Jake Cahill,
有立牌的地方就有好抽的红苹果香烟售卖
wherever fine Red Apple tobacco products are sold.
抽上一口  好好感受
Take a bite and feel all right.
来一口红苹果
Take a bite of a Red Apple.
就说是杰克派你来的
Tell them Jake sent you.
卡
And cut.
这烟真他妈难抽
This cigarette tastes like fucking shit.
还有  这是谁选的照片
And, by the way, who chose this photo?
我的双下巴都出来了好吗
I have a double chin. All right?
你们都瞎了吗
Nobody notices that crap?